<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EGI Documentation – Applications on Demand (AoD)</title><link>/users/applications-on-demand/</link><description>Recent content in Applications on Demand (AoD) on EGI Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/users/applications-on-demand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Users: Chipster</title><link>/users/applications-on-demand/chipster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/users/applications-on-demand/chipster/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://chipster.csc.fi/">Chipster&lt;/a> is a user-friendly software for analysing
high-throughput sequencing and microarray data, provided as part of EGI's
Applications on Demand service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The software contains over 400 analysis tools and a large collection of
reference genomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Users can save and share automatic analysis workflows, and visualize data
interactively using for example the built-in genome browser.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="egi-chipster">EGI Chipster&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Chipster testbed configured at &lt;a href="https://www.cesga.es/">CESGA&lt;/a> offers:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>8 vCPU cores,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>32GB of RAM,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1TB of block storage in /data,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Software and tools are in available under the &lt;code>/cvmfs/tools_*&lt;/code> partition,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chipster (v3.16.3).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For accessing this testbed you need to be a member of the
&lt;a href="../">Applications on Demand&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="createreview-a-temporary-account">Create/Review a temporary account&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Go to
&lt;a href="https://fgsg.egi.eu/egissod/web/ssod/chipster-accounts">Chipster entry in Science Software on Demand Portal&lt;/a>
and log in with your &lt;a href="../../check-in">EGI Check-In account&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first time you log in, you need to generate a temporary password by clicking
on the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Execute&amp;quot;&lt;/em> button, as shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./chipster-execute.png" alt="First log in with Chipster">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please refresh the web page after your password has been successfully generated.
Once the page is reloaded (see screenshot below) you are presented with a link
to access the
&lt;a href="http://chipster.aod.fedcloud.eu:8081/chipster.jnlp">Chipster server&lt;/a> that you
can access with the new credentials.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./chipster.png" alt="Chipster in Science Software on Demand">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your account has expired the Science Gateway will automatically generate a
new password for you. Just click on the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Show form&amp;quot;&lt;/em> button to manage your
credentials.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Acknowledgment&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Please provide appropriate acknowledgement of the use of this service in your
scientific publications. Here is an example:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This work used the EGI Applications on Demand service, which is co-funded by
the EOSC-hub project (grant number 777536)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Users: Exoscale vouchers</title><link>/users/applications-on-demand/exoscale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/users/applications-on-demand/exoscale/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In this section we describe how users can easily discover the
&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/services/applications-on-demand/">EGI Applications on Demand (AoD)&lt;/a>
service published in the
&lt;a href="https://marketplace.eosc-portal.eu/">EOSC portal Marketplace&lt;/a> and submit a
service-order request to deploy an elastic virtual cluster on the HNSciCloud
pilot services. The virtual cluster will be deployed and configured with the
requested software packages using the
&lt;a href="https://servproject.i3m.upv.es/ec3-ltos/">Elastic Cloud Compute Cluster (EC3)&lt;/a>
portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="submit-a-service-order-request-through-the-eosc-portal-marketplace">Submit a service-order request through the EOSC Portal Marketplace&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://marketplace.eosc-portal.eu/">EOSC Portal Marketplace&lt;/a> is a single
entry point where users can navigate the EOSC service catalogue, discover a
service of interest, get information about it, and place an order in a few
clicks by specifying the service requested along with the quantity, quality and
duration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the available services of the EOSC Marketplace are grouped in 8 main
categories and no authentication is required to browse and discover the list of
services published in the marketplace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exoscale vouchers can be used when selecting he Elastic Cloud Compute Cluster
(EC3) platform from the list of available services by submitting a service-order
request.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./ec3-eosc-marketplace.png" alt="The Elastic Cloud Compute Cluster (EC3) in the EOSC Portal Marketplace.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Placing orders in the EOSC Marketplace requires the user to authenticate. There
are two login options: use your personal academic credentials or use EGI
Check-in service. The first time you login into the marketplace requires some
extra information to be provided to configure the marketplace account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two different service options are available for EC3:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./ec3-service-options.png" alt="The Elastic Cloud Compute Cluster (EC3) service options.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To deploy the virtual cluster on the HNSciCloud pilot services, select the
voucher option and click on &lt;em>Next&lt;/em> and provide additional information for
profiling the order (e.g. the motivation for requesting the service).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Users with an existing Exoscale voucher to redeem can provide the voucherID
during the submission request. Otherwise, a valid voucherID will be provided
once the order if processed and accepted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the service order is submitted, the marketplace will send a notification
via email. Users can at any time the status of their orders through the user
dashboard. This dashboard shows the history of service order(s) submitted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./ec3-order-request.png" alt="Details of a service order request.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The service order request will be processed within 3 working days&lt;/strong>. The user
will be notified of the outcome of the evaluation via email.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="voucher-redemption">Voucher redemption&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In case the service order is accepted:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The user will be notified by the Marketplace with the instructions to redeem
the voucher (in case it was not provided), generate a client and secret keys
and access the Elastic Cloud Compute Cluster (EC3) portal.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To redeem an Exoscale voucher, open the provided voucher link included in the
email sent by the Marketplace within a web browser.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A typical link looks
like:&lt;a href="https://portal.exoscale.com/register?coupon=XXXXXXX">https://portal.exoscale.com/register?coupon=XXXXXXX&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter the email address and password you wish to use. Accept the terms and hit
sign up.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./exoscale-account-setup.png" alt="Accept the privacy license agreement and sign up.">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A validation email is sent. Check out your mailbox and click on the
verification link.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./exoscale-activation.png" alt="Activate the voucher clicking on the verification link.">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Choose &amp;ldquo;for team projects&amp;rdquo; and fill your details. Choose your &amp;ldquo;Company or team
name&amp;rdquo; and submit the form.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="access-to-the-exoscale-dashboard">Access to the Exoscale dashboard&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Access the &lt;a href="https://portal.exoscale.com/">Exoscale dashboard&lt;/a> and check the
tenant settings (click in the User profile on the left)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./exoscale-credentials.png" alt="Generate API and Secret Keys to access the Exoscale resources.">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="check-the-voucher-credit">Check the voucher credit&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Access the &lt;a href="https://portal.exoscale.com/">Exoscale dashboard&lt;/a>. The voucher
credit is shown in the top-right of the dashboard. In case voucher credit is
going to expire, a notification email will be sent by the dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deploy-a-virtual-cluster-on-the-exoscale-commercial-resources">Deploy a virtual cluster on the Exoscale commercial resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Through a &amp;ldquo;job wizard&amp;rdquo; interface (see Figures below) the user can login to the
Elastic Cloud Compute Cluster (EC3) portal and configure the virtual cluster
with the related tools and applications to be deployed on top of Infrastructure
as a Service (IaaS). The cluster is composed by a front node, where a batch job
scheduler is running, and a number of compute nodes. These compute nodes will be
dynamically deployed and provisioned to fit increasing load, and un-deployed
when they are in idle status. The installation and configuration of the cluster
is performed by means of the execution of Ansible receipts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./ec3-deployment.png" alt="Deployment of virtual clusters on Exoscale.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./ec3-wizard.png" alt="The EC3 job wizard to configuration the virtual cluster.">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgement-and-report-feedback">Acknowledgement and report feedback&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The user &lt;strong>MUST&lt;/strong> acknowledge the EOSC-hub and the HNSciCloud projects in the
scientific publications/presentations benefiting from the service. The following
acknowledgement statement can be used for this purpose:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;This work used the EGI Applications on Demand service, which is co-funded by
the EOSC-hub project (grant number 777536). The HNSciCloud project (grant
number 687614) is also sponsoring the service, allowing users to access the
HNSciCloud services pilot for limited scale usage using the voucher scheme
provided by Exoscale.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="report-feedback">Report feedback&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To report feedback on the Exoscale vouchers, please fill in the following web
form: &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/cVT7JRd4TFxZiYmQ8">https://forms.gle/cVT7JRd4TFxZiYmQ8&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>