<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EGI Documentation – Getting Started</title><link>/providers/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on EGI Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/providers/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Providers: Joining EGI as a provider</title><link>/providers/getting-started/joining/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/providers/getting-started/joining/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In these guidelines, we describe the set of actions a service provider should
follow to join the &lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/egi-infrastructure/">EGI Infrastructure&lt;/a>,
and to ensure the high-quality delivery of service according to the EGI
policies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Providers have different options to become members of the EGI Federation, and
deliver services for advanced computing within the EGI Infrastructure. The
options are documented below, linking to detailed instructions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../joining/federated-resource-centre">Joining as a federated resource centre&lt;/a>.
A provider (that we call Resource Centre) delivering one of the following
services: &lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/service/cloud-compute/">Cloud Compute&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/service/high-throughput-compute/">HTC Compute&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/service/cloud-container-compute/">Cloud Container Compute&lt;/a>,
or &lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/service/online-storage/">Online Storage&lt;/a>. More than
200 Resource Centres have been integrated in this way.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../joining/technology-provider/">Joining as a software provider&lt;/a>, also
called Technology Providers, which are the maintainers of the middleware
deployed on the ‘federated resource providers’ (previous point).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../joining/new-provider/">Joining as a new provider&lt;/a> for an existing
platform service in the Compute and Data Federation or the Platform services,
such as &lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/service/datahub/">DataHub&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/service/notebooks/">Notebooks&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/service/training-infrastructure/">Training Infrastructure&lt;/a>,
and &lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/service/workload-manager/">Workload Manager&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../joining/core-service/">Joining as Core/Central service provider&lt;/a>:
providers for
&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/services/federation/">services supporting all the other services of the EGI Infrastructure&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../joining/new-service/">Contributing a new service&lt;/a> that is not yet present
in the &lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/services/research/">EGI service portfolio&lt;/a> and
enables advanced computing in research and education.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Providers: Operations Start Guide</title><link>/providers/getting-started/operations-start-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/providers/getting-started/operations-start-guide/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Operations Start Guide will help you start with EGI Operations duties. It
covers the responsibilities of the various parties involved in the running of
the &lt;a href="https://ims.egi.eu/display/EGIG/EGI+Infrastructure">EGI infrastructure&lt;/a> and
guide how to join operations. As a newcomer, you need to understand the
structure of the infrastructure and roles of operators at different levels.
Reading the whole document will give you a complete overall picture of daily
operations within EGI.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resource-centres-and-resource-infrastructures">Resource Centres and Resource Infrastructures&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Resources are geographically distributed and are contributed by
&lt;a href="https://ims.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Resource+Centre">Resource Centres&lt;/a>. A Resource
Centre is the smallest resource administration domain within EGI. It can be
either localized or geographically distributed. A Resource Centre is also known
as a &lt;em>site&lt;/em>. It provides a minimum set of local or remote IT Services, such as
High Throughput Compute (HTC), Cloud Compute, Storage and Data Transfer,
compliant to well-defined IT Capabilities necessary to make resources accessible
to authorised users. Users can access the services using common interfaces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The EGI Federation is a
&lt;a href="https://ims.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Resource+Infrastructure">Resource Infrastructure&lt;/a>
federating Resource Centres to constitute a homogeneous operational domain, and
the
&lt;a href="https://ims.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Resource+Infrastructure+Provider">Resource Infrastructure Provider&lt;/a>
is the legal organisation that is responsible of establishing, managing and of
operating directly or indirectly the operational services to an agreed level of
quality needed by the Resource Centres and the user community. It holds the
responsibility of integrating them in EGI to enable uniform resource access and
sharing for the benefit of their consuming end users. Examples of a Resource
infrastructure Provider are the
&lt;a href="https://ims.egi.eu/display/EGIG/European+Intergovernmental+Research+Organisation">European Intergovernmental Research Organisations (EIRO)&lt;/a>
and the &lt;a href="https://ims.egi.eu/display/EGIG/NGI">NGIs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Europe, Resource Centres are required to be affiliated to the respective
NGIs, which (a) have a mandate to represent their national users community in
all matters falling within the scope of the EGI Infrastructure, and (b) are the
only organization having the mandate described in (a) for its country and thus
provide a single contact point at the national level.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="operations-centres">Operations Centres&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A Resource Infrastructure Provider is responsible for delivering, to different
groups of customers, a number of services, either technical or humans : services
supporting the activities of the given Resource Infrastructure Provider and
facilitating and making secure the access to the provided resources and
services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to contribute resources to EGI, a Resource Infrastructure Provider must
be associated to an
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Operations+Centre">Operations Centre&lt;/a>
which will deliver the services on behalf of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A single Operations Centre can be federated and operate services for multiple
Resource Infrastructure Providers. Federation of operations can be a
cost-effective approach for Resource Infrastructure Providers wishing to share
their effort and services, or in order to operate the infrastructures in an
early stage of maturity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Operations Centre provides services in collaboration with the respective
Resource Centres via the Resource Centre Operations Manager, and globally with
EGI Foundation and other Operations Centres.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Locally, Operations Centres are responsible for supporting the Resource
Centres, for monitoring their Quality of Service (QoS), for collecting
requirements and representing them in the EGI operations boards.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Globally they are in charge of contributing to the evolution of the EGI
Infrastructure.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="roles">Roles&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The following sections covers the roles that are commonly involved in the
operations of the EGI Infrastructure. The correspondent
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/GOCDB/Input_System_User_Documentation#Roles">roles defined in Configuration Database (GOCDB)&lt;/a>
give specific rights in the Configuration Database itself and in other EGI
services. There are roles whose scope is limited to the operation of a Resource
Centre. A number of other roles act on a higher level, involving the operations
activities related either to the NGI (Regional level) or to the EGI
infrastructure as a whole (global level). Other terms and definitions can be
found in the &lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/glossary">EGI Glossary&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="resource-centre-level">Resource Centre level&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="resource-centre-administrator">Resource Centre Administrator&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>An individual responsible for installing, operating, maintaining and supporting
one or more Resources or IT Services in a Resource Centre. In the scope of
Operations, Resource Centres (RC) administrators primarily receive and react on
incidents at their Resource Centre and on service requests notified through
tickets created on the &lt;a href="../../../internal/helpdesk">EGI Helpdesk service&lt;/a>. They
should respond to the tickets in a suitable time frame as defined in the
&lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/document/31">Resource Centre Operational Level Agreement (OLA)&lt;/a>
and be aware of the alarms at their site, eg. through the
&lt;a href="https://operations-portal.egi.eu">Operations Dashboard&lt;/a>. Sites &lt;strong>MUST&lt;/strong> only
operate supported middleware versions. This implies upgrading it regularly.
Emergency releases are treated in a special way. Resource Centre Administrators
&lt;strong>MUST&lt;/strong> react to security issues that are at a global level, but affect their
site. See
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/SEC03_EGI-CSIRT_Critical_Vulnerability_Handling">SEC03 EGI-CSIRT Critical Vulnerability Handling&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="resource-centre-operations-manager">Resource Centre Operations Manager&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>An individual who leads the Resource Centre operations, who is the official
technical contact person in the connected organisation, and who is locally
supported by a team of Resource Centre Administrators. The Resource Centre
Operations Manager is responsible for the site at the political and legal levels
and for signing the
&lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/public/ShowDocument?docid=31">Operational Level Agreement&lt;/a>)
between the Resource Centre and its hosting NGI. The Resource Centre Operations
Manager is also responsible for enforcing the EGI policies and procedures by the
Resource Centre and for assigning and approving the other site roles in the
Configuration Database. Further, they should ensure that administrators are
subscribed to the relevant mailing lists.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="resource-centre-security-officer">Resource Centre Security Officer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The person responsible for keeping the site compliant with the
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/EGI_CSIRT:Policies">EGI security policies&lt;/a>. They are
the primary contact for the &lt;a href="#ngi-security-officer">NGI Security officer&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="#egi-csirt">EGI Computer Security Incident Response Team (CSIRT)&lt;/a>. The Site
Security Officer deals with security incidents and shall respond to enquiries in
a timely fashion as defined in the collection of
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/EGI_CSIRT:Policies">security procedures and policies&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="regional-level">Regional level&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="regional-operator-on-duty-rod">Regional Operator on Duty (ROD)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A team responsible for solving problems and incidents in the infrastructure
according to agreed procedures. ROD teams monitor the Resource Centres in their
region, react to incidents identified by the monitoring tools, and oversee
incidents and related problems through to their resolution. They ensure that
incidents are properly recorded and that the solutions progress according to
specified time lines. They also provide support to Resource Centres and Virtual
Organisations (VOs) and provide support to oversight bodies in cases of
unresponsive Resource Centres. They ensure that all the necessary information is
available to all parties. The team is provided by each NGI and requires
procedural knowledge on the process (rather than technical skills) for their
work. New ROD team members are required to read the
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/Regional_Operator_on_Duty_welcome">ROD Welcome page&lt;/a>
and be familiar with
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/Regional_Operator_on_Duty">ROD wiki page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ngi-security-officer">NGI Security officer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The NGI Security Officer is member of the &lt;a href="#egi-csirt">EGI-CSIRT&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The NGI Security Officer coordinates the security activities within its NGI and
serves as the primary contact for all security related requests, in particular
from &lt;a href="#egi-csirts-irtf">EGI-CSIRT&amp;rsquo;s IRTF&lt;/a> concerning issues with the sites
within the NGI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Further, the NGI Security Officer is responsible for overseeing the security
related aspects of the operations of the NGI and coordinates the security
activities within its NGI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NGIs and Sites &lt;strong>MUST&lt;/strong> respond in a timely manner to the security requests and
alerts coming from the EGI-CSIRT&amp;rsquo;s IRTF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The NGI Security Officer name and contact address needs to be registered in the
&lt;a href="https://goc.egi.eu">Configuration Database (GOCDB)&lt;/a> and the information
maintained by the NGI.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ngi-operations-manager">NGI Operations manager&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The NGI Operations manager is the contact point for all operational matters and
represents the NGI within the
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIBG/Operations+Management+Board">Operations Management Board (OMB)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They are mainly responsible for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>keeping up to date the NGI entry in the Configuration Database and managing
the status of all sites under their NGI, and ensuring their information is
also kept current&lt;/li>
&lt;li>addressing problems with Site availability or reliability. The reports are
issued on a monthly basis and the NGI operations managers have 10 days to
respond to identified problems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>attending regular
&lt;a href="https://indico.egi.eu/category/19/">Operations Management Board meetings&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>All NGI operations management responsibilities are listed in the
&lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/document/463">Resource Infrastructure Provider OLA document&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="global-level">Global level&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="chief-operations-officer">Chief Operations Officer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Chief Operations Officer leads EGI Operations, and is responsible for
coordinating the operations of the infrastructure across the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="egi-csirt">EGI-CSIRT&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://csirt.egi.eu">EGI-CSIRT&lt;/a> is the official security coordination team and
contact point at project level.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://csirt.egi.eu">EGI-CSIRT site&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/EGI_CSIRT:RFC_2350">EGI-CSIRT profile according to RFC-2350&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://csirt.egi.eu/files/2020/11/EGI-CSIRT-ToR_V2_20190819.pdf">EGI-CSIRT Terms of References&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="egi-csirts-irtf">EGI-CSIRT&amp;rsquo;s IRTF&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>The Incident Response Team for the Federation (IRTF) is a subgroup of EGI-CSIRT
which acts as the primary contact for all security related requests concerning
the Federation and the projects the EGI Foundation is involved in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>EGI-CSIRTs IRTF provides the Security Officer on Duty role on a weekly rota
basis. Details are in the
&lt;a href="https://csirt.egi.eu/files/2020/11/EGI-CSIRT-ToR_V2_20190819.pdf">EGI-CSIRT Terms of References&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="egi-security-officer">EGI Security Officer&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The EGI Security Officer, having the EGI CSIRT Officer role in the Configuration
Database, is leading and coordinating EGI-CSIRT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of the EGI Security Officer is provided by a member of EGI-CSIRT&amp;rsquo;s IRTF
on a weekly rota basis.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="egi-foundation-sdis-team">EGI Foundation SDIS team&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://ims.egi.eu/display/EGIG/EGI+Foundation">EGI Foundation&lt;/a> Service
Delivery and Information Security (SDIS) team, formerly known as the EGI
Operations team, is responsible of
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIPP/EGI+Infrastructure+operations+oversight">coordinating and supporting the operational activities&lt;/a>
of all the EGI Infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="vo">VO&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A
&lt;a href="https://ims.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Virtual+organisation">Virtual Organisation (VO)&lt;/a>
is a group of users and, optionally, resources, often not bound to a single
institution or national borders, who, by reason of their common membership and
in sharing a common goal, are given authority to use a set of resources. Each VO
member signs the VO Acceptable Usage Policy (AUP) (during registration) which is
the policy describing the goals of the VO thereby defining the expected and
acceptable use of the resources by the users of the VO. User documentation can
be found &lt;a href="../../../users/">in the users section&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/User_Documentation">in the EGI Wiki&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="vo-manager">VO manager&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>An individual responsible for the management of the membership registry of the
VO ensuring its accuracy and integrity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="joining-operations">Joining operations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In order to join any of the organisational groups in your NGI, you will need to
go through the following steps in order:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="authentication">Authentication&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In general the authentication in EGI infrastructure works either with X509
personal certificates or through federated identities using
&lt;a href="../../check-in">Check-in&lt;/a>. For some services (HTC and Storage) the access is
granted only by using a X509 personal certificate due to legacy reasons: the
process of moving the authentication and authorisation mechanism to federated
identities has started but it will takes time before having everything compliant
with federated identities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="obtaining-a-x509-personal-certificate">Obtaining a X509 personal certificate&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If you do not already have a X509 personal certificate
&lt;a href="https://www.eugridpma.org/members/worldmap/">the EUGridPMA worlmap&lt;/a> provides a
map of all certification authorities according to the country (or NGI). Select
your country on the map to find out who is your local CA. Follow the procedure
of your local CA to request a certificate. When you have received your
certificate, install it into your web browser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If case of setting up a new Resource Centre please request Host certificates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>EUGridPMA provides
&lt;a href="https://www.eugridpma.org/your-identity/">a web page allowing to test your certificate&lt;/a>.
Please use this resource and contact your CA if your certificate does not work.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="create-a-federated-identity-registration-in-egi-check-in">Create a federated identity: registration in EGI Check-in&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>As soon as you try to access an EGI service with your federated identity, you
will be requested to register an account in EGI Check-in if not existing yet.
The &lt;a href="../../../users/check-in/signup/">Check-in sign up guide&lt;/a> explains how to
sign up for an EGI account. If you already own an account, you will be simply
asked to login through EGI Check-in.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="joining-dteam-vo">Joining dteam VO&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It is recommended to join the &lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/Dteam_vo">dteam VO&lt;/a> at
the &lt;a href="https://voms2.hellasgrid.gr:8443/voms/dteam/">dteam Registration&lt;/a> page. You
should request group membership for &lt;code>/dteam&lt;/code> and &lt;code>/dteam/YOUR_NGI&lt;/code>. The dteam
group manager will then be notified and review your application. The membership
to dteam VO is possible only by using a X09 personal certificate and it is
useful to test the RCs and to debug related issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="requesting-gocdb-access">Requesting GOCDB access&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Read
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/GOCDB/Input_System_User_Documentation">Input System User Documentation&lt;/a>
first.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to the &lt;a href="https://goc.egi.eu/">Configuration Database&lt;/a> and follow
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/GOCDB/Input_System_User_Documentation#Users_and_roles">the instruction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>All members &lt;strong>should notify their NGI operations manager&lt;/strong> about their role
requests, to be sure they are considered on time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="registering-into-ggus">Registering into GGUS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To register into GGUS please follow the
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=register">Central GGUS registration&lt;/a> link. GGUS can be
accessed either with your X509 personal certificate or with your federated
identity. Do not forget to apply for
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=register">the support role&lt;/a> as well. (The GGUS support
staff will approve you quickly as they get the notification automatically). To
get the supporter role with your federated identity, please enroll to the
&lt;a href="https://aai.egi.eu/registry/co_petitions/start/coef:69">GGUS Supporters group&lt;/a>
in Check-in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your NGI also have a local helpdesk interfaced with GGUS, please ensure that
you are properly registered also there: your NGI managers will take care of
that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="subscribing-to-mailing-lists">Subscribing to mailing lists&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>NGIs and Sites have local mailing lists for ROD team members and Site
Administrators respectively. Please ensure that you subscribe to them. Depending
on your role ask your NGI operations manager or Site operations manager to have
you included on the necessary mailing lists if there is no automatic
subscription process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NGI operations manager should contact &lt;code>operations@egi.eu&lt;/code> and state that wish to
be subscribed to noc-managers mailing list &lt;code>noc-managers@mailman.egi.eu&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="documentation">Documentation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Procedures and policies are accessible on the
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIPP/EGI+Federation+Procedures">EGI Policies and Procedures space&lt;/a>.
Additional documentation relevant to EGI operations is available at
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/Documentation">EGI Documentation wiki page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tools">Tools&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A list of services relevant to EGI operations can be found at
&lt;a href="../../../internal">the section about internal services&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Providers: Resource Centre Integration Check List</title><link>/providers/getting-started/integration_checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/providers/getting-started/integration_checklist/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This page provides an overview of what are the required steps to get a new
Resource Centre integrated into the EGI Federation.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Be aware of the
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/EGI_CSIRT:Policies">security policies&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Acceptance of the
&lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/public/ShowDocument?docid=31">RC OLA&lt;/a> (agreed with
the NGI the RC belongs to).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Registration on the
&lt;a href="../../../internal/configuration-database">Configuration Database&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>an entry for the resource centre was created&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Required mailing lists are registered&lt;/li>
&lt;li>people operating the services are registered&lt;/li>
&lt;li>service endpoints are registered associated to the proper service types
(&lt;a href="../../cloud-compute/registration">e.g. for cloud providers&lt;/a>), and the
flags &lt;em>monitored&lt;/em> and &lt;em>production&lt;/em> are set to &lt;em>yes&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Support through the &lt;a href="../../../internal/helpdesk">EGI Helpdesk service&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The RC name is listed in the GGUS fields “Affected site” and “Notify Site”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The site administrators can modify and reply to the tickets assigned to
their RC
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The Supporter role can be requested either directly on GGUS by using the
own X509 personal certificate or by
&lt;a href="https://aai.egi.eu/registry/co_petitions/start/coef:69">enrolling to the ggus-supporters&lt;/a>
group in Check-in.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Security:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>HTC: &lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/EGI_CSIRT:Pakiti_client">pakiti&lt;/a> is
installed and the outcome of the EGI CSIRT assessment is positive;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cloud: the
&lt;a href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/Cloud_Security_Questionnaire_for_Resource_Centres">EGI security Survey&lt;/a>
was sent to the EGI CSIRT and the outcome was positive.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>AAI:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>HTC/Storage Compliant with X509 certificates and VOMS attributes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../cloud-compute/openstack/#egi-aai">OpenStack clouds integration with Check-in&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../check-in/sp/">General integration with Check-in for SPs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Monitoring: the registered endpoints are automaticall detected by
&lt;a href="../../../internal/monitoring">ARGO&lt;/a> and monitored according to their type
registered in the Configuration Database.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../../internal/accounting">Accounting&lt;/a>: The accounting records are
properly sent to the accounting repository and displayed by the
&lt;a href="https://accounting.egi.eu/">Accounting Portal&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Accounting probes and &lt;a href="https://github.com/apel/ssm">APEL SSM&lt;/a> are properlly
installed and configured:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>HTC: &lt;a href="https://github.com/apel/apel">APEL client&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cloud: &lt;a href="https://github.com/IFCA/caso">cASO&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Information discovery:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>HTC/Storage: the information about compute and storage endpoints are
&lt;a href="../../operations-manuals/man01_how_to_publish_site_information/">published by the site-bdii into the Top-BDIIs&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cloud: site is
&lt;a href="../../cloud-compute/openstack/#catch-all-operations">added to the fedcloud-catchall-operations repository&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Middleware: latest version of technology products are installed using the
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/Middleware">UMD/CMD release&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Software distribution:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>HTC (Optional): &lt;a href="https://github.com/cvmfs-contrib/egi-cvmfs">CVMFS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cloud: VM image synchronisation is configured with a HEPIX VM image list
compliant software (e.g.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/the-cloudkeeper-project/cloudkeeper">cloudkeeper&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>