<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation – EGI Check-in</title><link>/users/aai/check-in/</link><description>Recent content in EGI Check-in on Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/users/aai/check-in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Users: Sign up for an EGI Account</title><link>/users/aai/check-in/signup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/users/aai/check-in/signup/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="sign-up">Sign up&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You need to sign up for an account for accessing the EGI services. As part of
this process you will be assigned a personal unique &lt;strong>EGI ID&lt;/strong> which will be
then used across all EGI tools and services. Follow the instructions below to
get started:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="https://aai.egi.eu/signup">https://aai.egi.eu/signup&lt;/a>. This will show you the identity provider
discovery page: browse through the list of Identity Providers to find your
Home Organisation, &lt;em>or, alternatively,&lt;/em> type the name of your Home
Organisation in the search box. Note that the names are localised based on
the selected language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-idp-discovery.png" alt="Check-in IdP discovery">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Enter your login credentials to authenticate yourself with your Home
Organisation&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After successful authentication, you may be prompted by your Home
Organisation to consent to the release of personal information to the &lt;strong>EGI
AAI Service Provider Proxy&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After successful authentication, you will be redirected to the EGI account
registration form. On the introductory page, click &lt;strong>Begin&lt;/strong> to start the
registration process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-sign-up-intro.png" alt="Check-in sign up intro">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>EGI requires some basic information from you, depending on the attributes
released by your Identity Provider, you may need to provide the values of the
missing attributes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-sign-up-attributes.png" alt="Check-in sign up attributes">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On the registration form, click &lt;strong>Review Terms and Conditions&lt;/strong>
(&lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/document/2623">Acceptable Use Policy and Conditions of Use - EGI AUP&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>If you agree to the Terms of Use, select the &lt;strong>I Agree&lt;/strong> option.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Important&lt;/h4>
You will not be able to agree
to the terms until you review them.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-tou-agreement.png" alt="Check-in ToU agreement">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Finally, click &lt;strong>Submit&lt;/strong> to submit your request.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Important&lt;/h4>
You will not be able to
submit your request until you agree to the terms.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After submitting your request, Check-in will send you an email with a
verification link. After you click that link, you&amp;rsquo;ll be taken to the request
confirmation page.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Important&lt;/h4>
If you do not find the email
in your Inbox, please check your Spam or Junk folder for an email from &amp;ldquo;EGI
AAI Notifications&amp;rdquo;. If you do find the email in these folders, mark the email
as &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;not spam&amp;rdquo; to ensure that you receive any future notifications
about your EGI ID.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After reviewing your request, click &lt;strong>Confirm&lt;/strong> and re-authenticate yourself
using the Identity Provider you selected before.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Note: After your registration has been completed, you can manage your profile
through the &lt;a href="https://aai.egi.eu/registry">EGI Account Registry portal&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="viewing-user-profile-information">Viewing user profile information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The profile includes all the information related to the user. This information
can be categorised as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="basic-profile">Basic profile&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Includes the basic information about your profile:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Name&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identifiers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Email addresses&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-profile-basic.png" alt="User profile">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="vogroup-membership-and-roles">VO/Group membership and roles&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Includes information about the Virtual Organisations (VOs) and groups the user is
member of and the roles assigned to the user within those VOs.
Check the &lt;a href="../joining-virtual-organisation">guide about VOs&lt;/a> for more details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-profile-vos.png" alt="VO/Group membership">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="linked-identities">Linked identities&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Information about linked identities to your account. Check the
&lt;a href="../linking">guide for linking accounts&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-profile-linked.png" alt="Linked identities">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="next-steps">Next steps&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once your Check-in account is ready you can check
&lt;a href="../linking">how to link it with different identities&lt;/a> or
&lt;a href="../joining-virtual-organisation">how to join an existing Virtual Organisation (VO)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Users: Linking Identities</title><link>/users/aai/check-in/linking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/users/aai/check-in/linking/</guid><description>
&lt;!--
// jscpd:ignore-start
-->
&lt;h2 id="linking-new-identities-to-your-egi-account">Linking new identities to your EGI Account&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Identity linking allows you to access EGI resources with your existing personal
EGI ID, using any of the login credentials you have linked to your account. You
can use any of your organisational or social login credentials for this purpose.
To link a new organisational or social identity to your EGI account:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Enter the following URL in a browser: &lt;a href="https://aai.egi.eu/registry">https://aai.egi.eu/registry&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>Login&lt;/strong> and authenticate using any of the login credentials &lt;em>already&lt;/em>
linked to your EGI account&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Navigate to &lt;strong>My EGI User Community Identity&lt;/strong> page in one of the following
ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>hover over your display name next to the gear icon on the top right corner
of the page; &lt;em>or, alternatively,&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>select &lt;strong>EGI User Community&lt;/strong> from the list of available Collaborations and
then click &lt;strong>My EGI User Community Identity&lt;/strong> from the &lt;strong>People&lt;/strong> menu&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-my-identity.png" alt="Check-in my identity">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under the &lt;strong>Organisational Identities&lt;/strong> section of your profile page, expand
&lt;strong>Actions&lt;/strong> menu and click &lt;strong>Link New Identity&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-link-new.png" alt="Link new identity">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On the introductory page for Identity Linking, click &lt;strong>Begin&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-link-intro.png" alt="Link new identity intro">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You will need to sign in using the login credentials from the
institutional/social identity provider you want to link to your account.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Warning&lt;/h4>
It is very important to escape
the identity provider selection, cached in the discovery page, before picking
the new one.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After successful authentication, the new Identity Provider will be available
under the Organizational Identities tab and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to access EGI
resources with your existing personal EGI ID using the login credentials of
the identity provider you selected in &lt;strong>Step 6&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-link-end.png" alt="Link new identity end">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="linking-your-certificate-to-your-egi-account">Linking your certificate to your EGI Account&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Certificate linking allows you to add the subject DN of your certificate to your
existing personal EGI ID. For this you need to import your certificate to your
browser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To link a subject DN to your EGI account:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Enter the following URL in a browser: &lt;a href="https://aai.egi.eu/registry">https://aai.egi.eu/registry&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>Login&lt;/strong> and authenticate using any of the login credentials &lt;em>already&lt;/em>
linked to your EGI account&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Navigate to &lt;strong>My EGI User Community Identity&lt;/strong> page in one of the following
ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>hover over your display name next to the gear icon on the top right corner
of the page; &lt;em>or, alternatively,&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>select &lt;strong>EGI User Community&lt;/strong> from the list of available Collaborations and
then click &lt;strong>My EGI User Community Identity&lt;/strong> from the &lt;strong>People&lt;/strong> menu&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-my-identity.png" alt="Check-in my identity">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Under the &lt;strong>Organisational Identities&lt;/strong> section of your profile page, expand
&lt;strong>Actions&lt;/strong> menu and click &lt;strong>Link New Identity&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-link-new.png" alt="Link new identity">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On the introductory page for Identity Linking, click &lt;strong>Begin&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-link-intro.png" alt="Link new identity intro">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Continuously, you will need to sign in using the IGTF Certificate Proxy.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Warning&lt;/h4>
It is very important to escape
the identity provider selection, cached in the discovery page, before picking
the new one.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-discovery-igft.png" alt="Check-in IdP discovery IGTF">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then select the certificate you want to link to your account from the popup
window.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-select-certificate.png" alt="Select certificate">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After successful authentication you will be redirected back to your EGI
Account. Also, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to access EGI resources with your existing
personal EGI ID using &lt;strong>IGTF Certificate Proxy&lt;/strong> and your certificate.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To verify that the subject DN is added to your EGI account scroll down to
&lt;strong>Organisational Identities&lt;/strong> and click on &lt;strong>view&lt;/strong> button in the row where
the source is
&lt;code>https://edugain-proxy.igtf.net/simplesaml/saml2/idp/metadata.php&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-list-organisational-ids.png" alt="List organisational identities">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Then scroll down to &lt;em>Certificates&lt;/em> and you should see the subject DN of your
certificate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-certificates-preview.png" alt="Certificates preview">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!--
// jscpd:ignore-end
--></description></item><item><title>Users: Joining a Virtual Organisation</title><link>/users/aai/check-in/joining-virtual-organisation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/users/aai/check-in/joining-virtual-organisation/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Virtual+organisation">Virtual Organisations (VOs)&lt;/a>
in Check-in are represented as Collaborative Organisation Units (COUs).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to join a Virtual Organisation you must have an EGI account. If you
don&amp;rsquo;t have, then first &lt;a href="../signup/">sign up for an EGI account&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Login to &lt;a href="https://aai.egi.eu/registry">Check-in registry&lt;/a> with your EGI account.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Expand the &lt;strong>People&lt;/strong> drop down menu and click &lt;strong>Enroll&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-people-enroll.png" alt="COmanage-people-enroll">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;strong>Begin&lt;/strong> link of the Enrollment flow of the VO you want to
join&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-join-example.png" alt="Join example">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;strong>Begin&lt;/strong> button to start the Enrollment flow&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-start-enroll.png" alt="Start enrollement flow">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>a. If there are no pending petitions the enrollment flow will continue as usual.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b. If there is one pending petition:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>b1. If its status is in Pending Approval you will see a page similar to this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-pending-petition-approval.png" alt="Pending Petition Under Approval">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;strong>Notify Approver(s) Again&lt;/strong> button and a reminder email will be sent to approver(s)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>Proceed with new enrollment&lt;/strong>, so a new enrollment flow will start&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>Delete and proceed with new enrollment&lt;/strong>.
In this case, the pending petition will be deleted and a new enrollment flow will be created.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>b2. If its status is not in &lt;code>Pending Approval&lt;/code>, &lt;code>Pending Confirmation&lt;/code> or
&lt;code>Finalized&lt;/code> you will see a page similar to this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-pending-petition-created.png" alt="Pending Petition">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;strong>Resume&lt;/strong> button and continue the enrollment flow&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>Proceed with new enrollment&lt;/strong>, so a new enrollment flow will start&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>Delete and proceed with new enrollment&lt;/strong>.
In this case, the pending petition will be deleted and a new enrollment flow will start.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>c. If there is more than one pending petition related to the enrollment flow:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-pending-petitions.png" alt="Pending Petitions">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where you can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;strong>View&lt;/strong> Button of each petition and review it. (see (b) use case above)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click &lt;strong>Proceed with new enrollment&lt;/strong> and a new enrollment flow will start&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Users: Obtaining Access/Refresh Tokens</title><link>/users/aai/check-in/obtaining-tokens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/users/aai/check-in/obtaining-tokens/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This page includes all the available ways to obtain OAuth tokens from EGI
Check-in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Users: Virtual Organisations</title><link>/users/aai/check-in/vos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/users/aai/check-in/vos/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A &lt;a href="https://ims.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Virtual+organisation">Virtual Organisation&lt;/a>
(VO) represents a research community and, in practice, it is just &lt;strong>a group of
users&lt;/strong>. VOs are created to organise a community of researchers, who can share
resources across the EGI Federation and other services to achieve a common goal,
as part of a scientific collaboration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./VOs.png" alt="Virtual Organisations">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="see-the-list-of-virtual-organisations">See the list of Virtual Organisations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Existing VOs can be found in the
&lt;a href="https://operations-portal.egi.eu/vo/a/list">EGI Operations Portal&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the icon under the “Details” column to access more detailed information
of the VO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="img-screenshot">&lt;img src="./OP_VO_details.png" alt="List of VOs in the Operations Portal">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-join-a-virtual-organisation">How to join a Virtual Organisation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are different ways to join a VO:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Contact the administrators of the VO (the VO Managers). They can send you an
invitation or a link to apply for membership in a VO.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some community services provide a link on their Websites to grant access to
their respective VOs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the enrolment URL that can be found in the detailed information of the
specific VO, in the
&lt;a href="https://operations-portal.egi.eu/vo/a/list">EGI Operations Portal&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p class="img-screenshot">&lt;img src="./OP_VO_enrolment_url.png" alt="Enrolment URL of a VO in the Operations Portal">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Often, your request to apply for VO membership will be evaluated by a VO Manager
before you are accepted in the VO.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-create-your-own-virtual-organisation">How to create your own Virtual Organisation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To register a new VO, access the
&lt;a href="https://operations-portal.egi.eu/vo/registration">VO registration page&lt;/a> of the
Operations Portal. You will need to log in via Check-in and fill in the &lt;strong>VO ID
card&lt;/strong>, which is the basic information for the VO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The VO registration process is detailed in the procedure
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIPP/PROC14+VO+Registration">PROC14 VO Registration&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The person registering a VO is considered the administrator of the VO, also
known as &lt;strong>VO Manager&lt;/strong>. Additional VO Managers do not need to be included at
the time of the VO creation, they
&lt;a href="keycloak/admins#adding-administrators-to-a-group">can be added later&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="manage-a-virtual-organisation">Manage a Virtual Organisation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A VO is managed by its VO Managers. VOs can have more than one administrator,
and they are responsible for the correct operation of the VO. The functions of
the VO Managers include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Evaluate membership requests and approve or reject them. This is an important
point, since membership in a VO may grant access to data or resources, so
normally a VO Manager should not accept members arbitrarily.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Attend security recommendations, provide information requested by the EGI
security teams and maintain the resources and users of the VO secure.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide information about the VO activities for EGI and for VO members (to
both people and sites).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>VOs can be structured in &lt;strong>groups&lt;/strong>, to organise the different permissions that
users have inside a community. For example, inside a VO there can be a group for
users that will manage cloud infrastructure, another group for users that access
a specific application, other group for users that will attend a workshop and
need access to Notebooks, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check-in offers two tools to organise a community:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="keycloak">Keycloak&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="perun">Perun&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Follow the links for detailed information on how to manage VO groups.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Users: Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>/users/aai/check-in/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/users/aai/check-in/faq/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="getting-help">Getting help&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Requests for technical assistance and other issues related to Check-in can be
obtained by sending an email to:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="mailto:checkin-support@mailman.egi.eu">checkin-support@mailman.egi.eu&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Alternatively, if you already have a Check-in account, the &lt;a href="https://helpdesk.ggus.eu/">EGI Helpdesk&lt;/a>
can be used. More information can be found in the
&lt;a href="https://docs.egi.eu/internal/helpdesk/user-guide/">Helpdesk documentation&lt;/a>. In that case,
submit a new ticket and make sure that the support unit is assigned to &amp;ldquo;Check-in (AAI)&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-support-unit.png" alt="Check-in support unit in HelpDesk">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="connect-to-check-in-an-idp-federated-in-an-hub-and-spoke-federations">Connect to Check-in an IdP federated in an hub and spoke federations&lt;/h2>
&lt;!-- markdownlint-disable line-length -->
&lt;h3 id="i-get-an-error-similar-to-error---egi-check-in-service-not-accessible-through-your-institution-surfconext-example">I get an error similar to: &amp;ldquo;Error - EGI Check-in Service not accessible through your institution&amp;rdquo; (SURFconext example)&lt;/h3>
&lt;!-- markdownlint-enable line-length -->
&lt;p>In case of a &amp;ldquo;hub and spoke&amp;rdquo; federation the federation coordinator may require
that the IdP administrators explicitly request to connect to a SP and let their
users to authenticate on these SP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In most of the cases this is not a configuration problem neither for the
Check-in service nor for the Identity provider. The connection needs to be
implemented in the hub and spoke IdP Proxy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One example of such federation is SURFconext, the national IdP federation for
research and education in the Netherlands operated by SURFnet. If you are using
credentials from a Dutch IdP in eduGAIN, the SURFconext administrator of your
institute needs to request the connection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="authentication-error-with-adfs-based-identity-providers">Authentication error with ADFS-based Identity Providers&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="why-do-i-get-the-error-below-after-successfully-authenticating-at-my-home-idp">Why do I get the error below after successfully authenticating at my Home IdP?&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-plaintext" data-lang="plaintext">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>opensaml::FatalProfileException at (https://aai.egi.eu/registry.sso/SAML2/POST)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>SAML response reported an IdP error.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Error from identity provider:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Status: urn:oasis:names:tc:SAML:2.0:status:Responder
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The Responder error status is typically returned from ADFS-based IdP
implementations (notably Microsoft ADFS 2.0 and ADFS 3.0) that cannot properly
handle
&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-za/azure/active-directory/develop/active-directory-single-sign-on-protocol-reference#scoping%3E">Scoping elements&lt;/a>.
Check-in can be configured to omit the scoping element from the authentication
requests sent to such IdPs in order to allow successful logins. Please send an
email to the Check-in Support team using &lt;code>checkin-support&lt;/code> &lt;code>&amp;lt;AT&amp;gt;&lt;/code>
&lt;code>mailman.egi.eu&lt;/code> and include a screenshot of your error.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- markdownlint-disable line-length -->
&lt;h2 id="i-have-linked-an-igtf-x509-certificate-to-my-check-in-identity-but-the-information-is-inaccurate-or-incomplete">I have linked an IGTF X.509 certificate to my Check-in identity but the information is inaccurate or incomplete&lt;/h2>
&lt;!-- markdownlint-enable line-length -->
&lt;h3 id="what-can-i-do">What can I do?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To update your certificate information, follow these steps to log into your
Check-in profile page using your IGTF certificate:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Click
&lt;a href="https://aai.egi.eu/proxy/saml2/idp/SingleLogoutService.php?ReturnTo=https%3A%2F%2Faai.egi.eu%2Fregistry%2Fauth%2Flogin">here&lt;/a>
to access your profile page&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Warning&lt;/h4>
This may log you out of any
service you have accessed with Check-in on this browser!
&lt;/div>
2. On
the Check-in identity provider discovery page, select &lt;strong>IGTF&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Warning&lt;/h4>
If prompted to log in with a
different identity provider, click &lt;strong>CHOOSE ANOTHER ACCOUNT&lt;/strong> and then select
&lt;strong>IGTF&lt;/strong>. Alternatively, you can click
&lt;a href="https://aai.egi.eu/registry/auth/login?idphint=https%3A%2F%2Fedugain-proxy.igtf.net%2Fsimplesaml%2Fsaml2%2Fidp%2Fmetadata.php">here&lt;/a>
for your convenience
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="./check-in-discovery-igft.png" alt="Check-in IdP discovery IGTF">&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>