<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation – Community Specific Documentation</title><link>/users/getting-started/communities/</link><description>Recent content in Community Specific Documentation on Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/users/getting-started/communities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Users: Pangeo</title><link>/users/getting-started/communities/pangeo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/users/getting-started/communities/pangeo/</guid><description>
&lt;p>EGI and the Pangeo community in Europe have forged
&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/case-study/pangeo/">a collaboration&lt;/a>
to provide deployments of the Pangeo ecosystem using the computing
resources offered by the European Open Science Cloud
(&lt;a href="https://open-science-cloud.ec.europa.eu/">EOSC&lt;/a>). Read on to learn more about
how to get involved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-the-pangeo-community-in-europe">About the Pangeo community in Europe&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Many scientific domains have been transformed into data-driven disciplines.
Research projects increasingly and crucially depend on the exchange and
processing of data and have developed platforms tailored to their needs.
&lt;a href="https://pangeo.io/">Pangeo&lt;/a>, a world-wide community driven platform initially
developed for Geoscience, has a huge potential to become a common gateway able
to leverage a wide variety of infrastructures and data providers for various
science fields.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Public pangeo deployments that are providing fast access to large amounts of
data and compute resources are all USA-based and members from the Pangeo
community in Europe do not have a shared platform where scientists or
technologists can exchange know-how. The main objective of this collaboration
with EGI is to demonstrate how to deploy and use Pangeo on EOSC and underlined
the benefits for the European community.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-get-involved">How to get involved&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>EGI and the Pangeo community in Europe are interacting openly via a GitHub
repository: &lt;a href="https://github.com/pangeo-data/pangeo-eosc/">pangeo-eosc&lt;/a>. Visit
this repository to find publications coming out of this collaboration and
guides on how to get started
&lt;a href="https://github.com/pangeo-data/pangeo-eosc/blob/main/users/users-getting-started.md">as a user&lt;/a>
or &lt;a href="https://github.com/pangeo-data/pangeo-eosc/blob/main/providers/providers-getting-started.md">as a provider&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>