<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EGI Documentation – Features</title><link>/internal/helpdesk/features/</link><description>Recent content in Features on EGI Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/internal/helpdesk/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Internal: 'Notify Site' field and tickets to multiple sites</title><link>/internal/helpdesk/features/tickets-to-multiple-sites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/internal/helpdesk/features/tickets-to-multiple-sites/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="notify-site-field">Notify Site field&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The list of sites included in the drop-down menu of the &amp;ldquo;Notify site&amp;rdquo; field is
taken from GOCDB (EGI sites) and from OIM DB (OSG sites).
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Sites registered in OIM are only visible if they have status &amp;ldquo;enabled&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sites registered in GOC DB are only visible if they have status &amp;ldquo;certified&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sites in other states (e.g. &amp;ldquo;suspended&amp;rdquo;) are not visible in the &amp;ldquo;Notify
sites&amp;rdquo; drop-down list.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the sites information is synchronized once per night.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In case a site&amp;rsquo;s status changes, the site disappears from the &amp;ldquo;Notify sites&amp;rdquo;
drop-down list. Existing GGUS tickets related to this site get the &amp;ldquo;Notify
sites&amp;rdquo; field flushed. The NGI to which the site belongs inherits the ticket
from the site and is in charge of further processing this ticket.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="notify-multiple-sites-option">Notify multiple sites option&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Notifying multiple sites is a feature for submitting tickets with the same
topic against an unlimited number of sites in GGUS.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This feature can be used only by users owning a dedicated privileges.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There is a specific submit form linked from GGUS ticket submit area. In the
&amp;ldquo;Notify SITE&amp;rdquo; drop-down menu sites can be checked for receiving a ticket.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All sites registered in GGUS can be notified using this option.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Internal: Alarm tickets</title><link>/internal/helpdesk/features/alarm-tickets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/internal/helpdesk/features/alarm-tickets/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction-purpose-and-conditions">Introduction: purpose and conditions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The purpose of ALARM tickets is to notify WLCG Tier-0 and Tier-1
administrators about serious problems of the site at any time, independent
from usual office hours.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Only experts, nominated by the WLCG VOs are allowed to submit alarm tickets.
They need to have the appropriate permissions in GGUS user database.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The involved VOs are:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Alice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Atlas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lhcb&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Only the Tier-0 &amp;amp; Tier-1 sites are involved in the alarm tickets process. The
WLCG Tier-0/Tier-1 site names can be used as well as the relevant GOC DB site
names.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Alarm tickets are routed to the NGI/ROC the tier site belongs to
automatically. They do not need a routing by the TPM. The NGI/ROC is notified
about the ticket in the usual way. In parallel the site receives an alarm
email signed with a GGUS certificate. This alarm email is processed at the
Tier-0/Tier-1 and notifies the relevant people at any time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Alarm email addresses are taken from GOC DB for the EGI sites and from OIM for
the OSG sites. VOMS is used by GGUS as the information source for authorised
alarmers.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="LHC_T1s.png" alt="Tier 1s picture">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="becoming-an-alarm-ticket-member">Becoming an Alarm-ticket member&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>People who want to become an alarmer have to&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>register in GGUS first&lt;/li>
&lt;li>be added to the appropriate group in a VOMS server.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>GGUS system synchronizes its user database once per night with the VOMS servers.
The synchronization is based on the DN string. Please make sure the DN of your
GGUS account is the same than the one registered in VOMS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tier-1 site admins can become alarmers for testing the alarm process for their
site. They have to fill in the
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=register">registration form&lt;/a> for supporters. Please add
an appropriate comment (e.g. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a xxx tier-1 site admins and I want to become
an alarmer for testing purposes.&amp;quot;) in the registration form.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="technical-description">Technical description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This section describes the workflows of alarm tickets from a technical point of
view.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="alarm-ticket-submission">ALARM ticket submission&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Alarm tickets can be submitted using the GGUS web portal. On top of the ticket
submit form in GGUS web portal there is a link to the submit form for alarm
tickets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Alarm_Submit_Link.png" alt="Link to Alarm tickets submit form">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As alarm ticket submitters are experts who will hopefully provide all necessary
information, the number of fields on the alarm ticket submit form is reduced to
a minimum compared to the number of fields on the user ticket submit form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Alarm_Submit_Form.png" alt="Alarm tickets submit form">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Three fields on this form are mandatory:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Subject&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MoU Area&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Notified Site&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>All other fields are optional.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="alarm-ticket-processing">ALARM ticket processing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The processing of a team ticket consists of two main parts: the notification of
the notified site and the routing of the ticket to the NGI/ROC the site belongs
to.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="tier-1-site-notification">Tier-1 site notification&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In parallel to the creation of an alarm ticket, the GGUS system sends an alarm
email directly to the tier 1 site specified in field “Notify SITE”. This email
is sent to a specific site alarm mail address and signed with the GGUS
certificate. The tier-0 alarm mail address is based on the VO name. It is
&amp;ldquo;voname&amp;rdquo;-operator-alarm&amp;quot;atnospam&amp;quot;cern.ch. Tier-1 site alarm mail addresses are
taken from the &amp;ldquo;Emergency Email&amp;rdquo; field in GOC DB. For tier-1 sites registered in
the OSG OIM DB the alarm email address is taken from field &amp;ldquo;SMSAddress&amp;rdquo; of the
&amp;ldquo;Administrative Contact&amp;rdquo; in OIM DB. The DN of the GGUS certificate is
/C=DE/O=GermanGrid/OU=KIT/CN=ggusmail/ggus.eu. The alarm mail looks like the
following figure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Alarm_Notify_Mail.png" alt="alarm notify email">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ticket-routing">Ticket routing&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Alarm tickets are bypassing the TPMs and routed to the appropriate NGI/ROC
automatically. The decision to which NGI/ROC a ticket has to be routed is done
automatically, based on the value of the “Notify SITE” field. The “Notify SITE”
drop-down menu shows both the tier 1 site names from GOC DB and the tier 1 site
names used by WLCG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Alarm_T1_Dropdown.png" alt="T1 dropdown menu">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="alarm-confirmation">ALARM confirmation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Once the tier 1 site received the alarm email the receipt should be confirmed.
Sending a reply mail containing the typical GGUS identifier and the ticket ID
“GGUS-Ticket-ID: #00000000” in the subject is sufficient. Such a reply will be
added to the alarm ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="working-on-alarm-tickets">Working on ALARM tickets&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For working on alarm tickets and resolving them please use the GGUS portal. A
reference link to the alarm ticket is given in the alarm email notification.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="periodic-alarm-ticket-testing-rules">Periodic ALARM ticket testing rules&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Alarm ticket testing is documented in
&lt;a href="https://twiki.cern.ch/twiki/bin/view/EGEE/SA1_USAG#Periodic_ALARM_ticket_testing_ru">WLCG twiki&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Internal: Quality of Support (QoS) levels</title><link>/internal/helpdesk/features/quality-of-support-levels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/internal/helpdesk/features/quality-of-support-levels/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>QoS stands for Quality of Support. It describes the level of support provided by
Support Units in GGUS system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has an impact on the ticket
&lt;a href="../features/ticket-priority">priority colour&lt;/a> in GGUS and the warnings are sent
to SUs if 75% of the maximum response time of the QoS level are over.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="qos-levels">QoS levels&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are three different QoS levels, each defining different response times for
given Ticket Priority.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Base&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Medium&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Advanced&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The defaut QoS level, if not declared differently, is &lt;strong>Base&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="base-level">Base Level&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Base QoS level defines a response time of &lt;strong>5 working days&lt;/strong> regardless of the
ticket priority.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="medium-level">Medium Level&lt;/h3>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Ticket Priority&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Response time&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>less urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>5 working days&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>5 working days&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>very urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1 working day&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>top priority&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1 working day&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h3 id="advanced-service">Advanced service&lt;/h3>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Ticket Priority&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Response time&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>less urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>5 working days&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1 working day&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>very urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1 working day&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>top priority&lt;/td>
&lt;td>4 working hours&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="qos-level-declaration">QoS level declaration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The QoS level for all of the SUs are available
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=resp_unit_info">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the several EGI services, the QoS levels are defined in the specific
Operational Level Agreements linked in the
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGISLM/EGI+OLA+SLA+framework#EGIOLASLAframework-OperationalLevelAgreements">EGI OLA SLA framework page&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Internal: Report generator</title><link>/internal/helpdesk/features/report-generator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/internal/helpdesk/features/report-generator/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="definitions-and-prerequisites">Definitions and prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=report_view">GGUS Report Generator&lt;/a> is available
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=support">from the support section&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The implementation of the report generator started in October 2011. Hence the
report generator does not provide data for tickets submitted before December
2011!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="timestamps-and-metrics">Timestamps and metrics&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>submit timestamp: timestamp when the ticket is submitted&lt;/li>
&lt;li>assign timestamp: timestamp when a ticket gets assigned to a support unit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>response timestamp: timestamp when the ticket status changes from &amp;ldquo;assigned&amp;rdquo;
to any other status value or the ticket gets re-assigned to another support
unit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>expected response timestamp: timestamp when a ticket should have changed the
status to any other status value than &amp;ldquo;assigned&amp;rdquo; or be re-assigned to another
support unit at latest&lt;/li>
&lt;li>solution timestamp: timestamp when the status changes to either &amp;ldquo;solved&amp;rdquo; or
&amp;ldquo;unsolved&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="response-time">Response time&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The response time is a performance figure calculated from the support unit&amp;rsquo;s
point of view. It describes how quick a support unit is reacting on tickets.
Response time is the time from&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>either assigning a ticket to a support unit and the support unit is kept until
the first status changes to any other value than &amp;ldquo;assigned&amp;rdquo;, or&lt;/li>
&lt;li>assigning a ticket to a support unit and the status value &amp;ldquo;assigned&amp;rdquo; is kept
until the support unit changes to any other support unit (re-assign).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The response time is calculated as difference between the timestamp changing the
status or re-assigning the ticket and the assign timestamp. While assigning a
ticket to a support unit the expected response timestamp is calculated by adding
an amount of time to the assign timestamp. The amount of time added depends on
the ticket priority and the kind of support unit. For support units that have
declared a quality of service level the response times are defined by the
&lt;a href="../features/quality-of-support-levels">QoS level&lt;/a>. For all the
other support units a medium QoS is assumed for calculating the expected
response timestamp. In case the actual response timestamp is greater than the
&amp;ldquo;expected response&amp;rdquo; timestamp for middleware support units the &amp;ldquo;violate&amp;rdquo; flag is
set.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Response times are based on office hours. Hence the results unit is working
days.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="solution-time">Solution time&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The solution time is a performance figure also calculated from the support
unit&amp;rsquo;s point of view. It describes how long it took the support unit for
providing a solution. Solution time is the time from assigning a ticket to a
support unit until it provides a solution for the problem described. &amp;ldquo;Providing
a solution&amp;rdquo; means setting the ticket status to &amp;ldquo;solved&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;unsolved&amp;rdquo;. The
solution time is calculated as the difference between the solution timestamp and
the assign timestamp.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Solution times are based on office hours. Hence the results unit is working
days.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="waiting-time">Waiting time&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Waiting time is the sum of all time slots the ticket was set to &amp;ldquo;waiting for
reply&amp;rdquo;. Calculating the waiting time has started in July 2012. For tickets
submitted before July 2012 no waiting time calculation was done. The waiting
time for these tickets may be zero. The waiting time can be excluded when
calculation solution times by ticking the checkbox &amp;ldquo;exclude waiting time&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ticket-lifetime">Ticket lifetime&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The ticket lifetime is calculated from the user&amp;rsquo;s point of view. It describes
how long it takes to provide a meaningful solution for a problem reported by the
user. Ticket lifetime is the time from ticket submission to ticket solution
(status &amp;ldquo;solved/unsolved&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The ticket lifetime is based on calendar days.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="time-zones">Time zones&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>GGUS support units are spread over a wide range of time zones. Some of the
support units themselves are spread over several time zones. However most
support units are located in European time zones. Support units and their time
zones are listed on &lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=resp_unit_info">a dedicated page&lt;/a>.
For middleware product teams GGUS assumes time zone &amp;ldquo;UTC +1&amp;rdquo; for all support
units. For all the other support units the system uses the relevant time zone
for calculating timestamps as far as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="office-hours">Office hours&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The systems assumes usual office hours from 09:00 to 17:00 Monday to Friday for
all support units. National holidays are not taken into account. For middleware
product teams the timezone UTC+1 is used as default timezone.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ticket-priorities">Ticket priorities&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For the calculation of performance figures the original priority set during
ticket submission is used. This priority value is kept as long as the support
unit is in charge of the ticket. Updating the priority value during ticket
lifetime doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect the calculation of performance figures.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="unit-abbreviations">Unit abbreviations&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>[wd] means working days&lt;/li>
&lt;li>[d] means calendar days&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="reports-description">Reports description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Although some of the drop-down lists request the selection of values a query
can be started anyway. In this case the query is equivalent to a query over all
tickets!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &amp;ldquo;Reset&amp;rdquo; button resets all fields to their default settings besides the time
frame.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tickets-submitted">Tickets submitted&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This metric gives the number of tickets submitted within the specified time
frame. Major criteria is the submit timestamp. The result lists shows the
&lt;strong>current&lt;/strong> status of the tickets.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="open-tickets-time">Open tickets time&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The open tickets time report calculates the time from ticket submission until
now in calendar days. The &lt;strong>submit timestamp&lt;/strong> must match the specified time
frame for the report.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tickets-closed">Tickets closed&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This metric is focused on the &lt;strong>ticket life time&lt;/strong>. It gives the number of
tickets that reached the status &amp;ldquo;solved&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;unsolved&amp;rdquo; within the specified time
frame. Major criteria is the &lt;strong>solution timestamp&lt;/strong> which is the timestamp
setting a ticket to &amp;ldquo;solved&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;unsolved&amp;rdquo;. Tickets in other terminal status
like &amp;ldquo;verified&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;closed&amp;rdquo; appear in the result list as long as they have been
set to &amp;ldquo;solved/unsolved&amp;rdquo; in the given time frame. Besides date, status and the
number of closed tickets the results list displays the average ticket lifetime
and the median ticket lifetime. The result lists shows the current status of the
tickets.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="response-time-1">Response time&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This metric focuses on the responsiveness of support units. Major criteria for
this report is the &lt;strong>submit timestamp&lt;/strong> which must match the selected time
frame. The result list shows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the number of tickets responded&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the number of responses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>average response time and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>median response time&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>for the specified time frame. The result list shows all support units that have
ever been in charge of a ticket. Hence the same ticket ID may appear several
times. The number of responses may be greater than the number of tickets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Response times are based on office hours. Hence an average response time of 1d
3h 23min means 13 hours and 23 minutes in total.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="violated-response-time">Violated response time&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Specific privileges are required for this report. Only people belonging to a
dedicated technology provider (TP) are able doing reports for this TP. Major
criteria for this report are the &lt;strong>expected response time&lt;/strong> defined in SLAs and
the TP.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="solution-time-1">Solution time&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Major criteria for this report is the &lt;strong>solution timestamp&lt;/strong>. The result list
shows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the number of solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>average response time and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>median response time&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>for the specified time frame. The result lists shows the current status of the
tickets. &lt;em>Solution times are based on office hours. Hence an average solution
time of 12d 3h 5min means 99 hours and 5 minutes in total.&lt;/em> The waiting time can
be excluded by ticking the checkbox &amp;ldquo;exclude waiting time&amp;rdquo;. In case a ticket
gets re-opened the metrics calculation starts again from scratch. Hence the same
ticket can appear several times in the solution times calculation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="input-parameters-and-results">Input parameters and results&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="input-parameters">Input parameters&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The input parameters vary depending on the report type chosen. Possible input
parameters are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Time frame&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Responsible Unit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Status&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Priority&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Concerned VO&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ticket type&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ticket category&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ticket Scope&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Notified site&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technology provider&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Date aggregation&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="time-frame">Time frame&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The time frame defines begin and end date of the report. The begin date starts
at 00:00:00. The end date ends at 00:00:00. As the implementation of the report
generator started in October 2011 the report generator does not provide data for
tickets submitted before December 2011!&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="responsible-units">Responsible Units&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The drop-down list offers all responsible units integrated in GGUS system. They
can be filtered by keywords. Responsible Units can be either selected all, one
by one or by checking the boxes in front of the responsible unit groups. In case
no responsible units are selected all responsible units are considered in the
reports.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="status">Status&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The drop-down list offers all status values available in GGUS system. Multiple
selections are possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="priority">Priority&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The drop-down list offers all priority values available in GGUS system. Multiple
selections are possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="concerned-vo">Concerned VO&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Concerned VO&amp;rdquo; provides a drop-down list of all VOs supported by GGUS. Multiple
selections are possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ticket-type">Ticket type&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This drop-down list lists all ticket types in GGUS. Multiple selections are
possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ticket-category">Ticket category&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Selectable categories are &amp;ldquo;Incident&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Change request&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Documentation&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Test&amp;rdquo;.
Multiple selections are possible. The category &amp;ldquo;Test&amp;rdquo; should not be considered
for all reports and therefore, if necessary, be excluded from the selection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ticket-scope">Ticket scope&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To distinguish between tickets under the responsibility of EGI or WLCG.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="notified-site">Notified site&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Notified site&amp;rdquo; lists all sites integrated in GGUS. They are derived from GOC DB
and OIM DB. In case of reporting exclusively on tickets without any site value
specified please ticket the &amp;ldquo;blank&amp;rdquo; value in the drop-down list.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="technology-provider">Technology Provider&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This input parameter is only visible if choosing the &amp;ldquo;violated response time&amp;rdquo;
report. For accessing this report specific privileges are required. The
drop-down list offers all technology providers currently integrated in GGUS and
the &amp;ldquo;DMSU&amp;rdquo;. Multiple selections are possible. In case no technology provider is
selected the reports will be done for tickets without any technology provider
specified.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="date-aggregation">Date aggregation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The results aggregation level can be chosen from the drop down list &amp;ldquo;Choose date
aggregation&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="group-by">Group by&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Results can be grouped by one or more of the input parameters.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="results">Results&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The results are displayed below the input parameter area. They can be sorted in
different ways by clicking on the column labels. A drill-down is possible by
clicking on any row of the results list. The detail results open in a new
window. They can be sorted by clicking the column labels too. Clicking on the
ticket ID opens the ticket in GGUS system. At the bottom of the result panel
there are various icons offering features like:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Search&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Refresh&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Export&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Export what you see&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Doing a simple &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Export&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> saves the data in a csv file stripping all column
headers. For exporting the data including the column headers please use &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Export
what you see&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>. The &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Search&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> feature allows searching in the result list.
Possible search parameters are the columns of the result list.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Internal: Team tickets</title><link>/internal/helpdesk/features/team-tickets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/internal/helpdesk/features/team-tickets/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction-purpose-and-conditions">Introduction: purpose and conditions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The purpose of TEAM tickets is to allow all team members to modify all tickets
of their team although they may not have support access and they do not have
submitted the ticket themselves.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Only members of a few VOs are allowed to submit team tickets:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Alice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Atlas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CMS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>LHCb&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Biomed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Belle&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The VO menbers need to have the appropriate permissions in GGUS user database&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Other VOs can request this functionality by opening a GGUS ticket&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Team tickets are routed to the NGI/ROC the site belongs to automatically. They
do not need a routing by the TPM. The NGI/ROC is notified about the ticket in
the usual way. In parallel, the site receives a notification email.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="becoming-a-team-ticket-member">Becoming a Team-ticket member&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>People who want to become a team member have to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>register in GGUS first&lt;/li>
&lt;li>be added to the appropriate group in a VOMS server.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>GGUS system synchronizes its user database once per night with the VOMS servers.
The synchronization is based on the DN string. Please make sure the DN of your
GGUS account is the same to the one registered in VOMS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="technical-description">Technical description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This section describes the workflows of team tickets from a technical point of
view.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="team-ticket-submission">Team ticket submission&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Team tickets can either be submitted using the GGUS web portal. On top of the
ticket submit form in GGUS web portal there is a link to the submit form for
team tickets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Submit_Team.png" alt="link to submit form for team tickets">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As team ticket submitters are expected to be experts who will hopefully provide
all necessary information, the number of fields on the team ticket submit form
is reduced to a minimum, compared to the number of fields on the user ticket
submit form&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Submit_Form_Team.png" alt="Submit form for team tickets">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Three fields on this form are mandatory:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Subject&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MoU Area&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Notified Site&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>All of the other fields are optional.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="team-ticket-processing">Team ticket processing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The processing of a team ticket consists of two main parts, the notification of
the notified site and the routing of the ticket to the NGI/ROC the site belongs
to.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="site-notification">Site notification&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In parallel to the creation of a team ticket the GGUS system sends an email
notification directly to the site specified in field “Notify Site”. This email
is sent to a specific site contact mail address.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ticket-routing">Ticket routing&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Team tickets are bypassing the TPMs and routed to the appropriate NGI/ROCs
automatically as long as field &amp;ldquo;Routing type&amp;rdquo; is not changed. The decision to
which NGI/ROC a ticket has to be routed is done automatically, based on the
value of the “Notify Site” field.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="working-on-team-tickets">Working on team tickets&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For working on team tickets and resolving please use the GGUS portal. A
reference link to the team ticket is given in the team notification mail. Team
tickets can be upgraded to alarm tickets clicking on the button “Click to
convert to ALARM”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Team_to_alarm.png" alt="Team to Alarm">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Internal: Ticket Priority</title><link>/internal/helpdesk/features/ticket-priority/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/internal/helpdesk/features/ticket-priority/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="priority-definition">Priority definition&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you plan to adjust the ticket priority from the default value &amp;lsquo;less urgent&amp;rsquo;
to &amp;lsquo;urgent&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;very urgent&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;top priority&amp;rsquo;, please make sure you add a
justification for this change in the problem description field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following table will help you to find an appropriate priority value:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Priority&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Comment&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>top priority&lt;/td>
&lt;td>service interrupted; needs to be addressed as soon as possible&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>very urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>service degraded; no work-around available&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>service degraded; work-around available&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>less urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>wishes and enhancements that are &amp;ldquo;nice to have&amp;rdquo;&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>In particular, be very economical when choosing &amp;lsquo;top priority&amp;rsquo;. This value, when
reaching the supporters via another ticketing system interface, might become a
beep or phone alert even in the middle of the night. This level of support is
ONLY committed by WLCG Tier0 and Tier1s and ONLY for ALARM tickets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, please be aware that the supporter who will try to solve your problem
may change the value you have chosen to a more realistic one, putting their
justification in the ticket&amp;rsquo;s public diary.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="priority-colours">Priority colours&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="the-purpose-of-the-priority-colours-in-ggus">The purpose of the priority colours in GGUS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The priority colours in GGUS should help supporters getting an overview of the
most important tickets. The priority colours have no impact on the metrics
generated with the GGUS report generator or manually by the GGUS team.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-colours-used">The colours used&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Currently the following colours are used for open states:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>green&lt;/li>
&lt;li>yellow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>amber&lt;/li>
&lt;li>red&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For terminal states GGUS uses:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>light blue for status “unsolved” and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>blue for status “solved” and “verified”.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="fields-affecting-the-priority-colour-algorithm">Fields affecting the priority colour algorithm&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The priority colour algorithm is affected by the status value and the priority
of a ticket. The priority colour calculation for tickets in status &amp;ldquo;assigned&amp;rdquo; is
based on different values than for tickets in any other open status.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="office-hours-and-weekends">Office hours and weekends&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Office hours and weekends are taken into consideration when calculating the
priority colour. The system assumes usual office hours from 07:00 to 15:00
o’clock UTC from Monday to Friday for all support units. Different time zones
are considered as far as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="priority-colour-and-status-values">Priority colour and status values&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The priority colour calculation starts after a ticket gets assigned to any
support unit. The support units should change the ticket status to &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo;
or any other open status after receiving the ticket. Thus the support unit has
responded to the ticket (response time). After such a status change the priority
is reset to &amp;ldquo;green&amp;rdquo; and the calculation of the priority colour starts again from
scratch.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="algorithm-for-middleware-related-tickets">Algorithm for middleware related tickets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The priority colour for tickets dealing with middleware related problems is
calculated according to the Quality of Support the PTs voted for. The priority
colour changes after a dedicated amount of working hours as listed in the table
below. The priority colour calculation is processed every 15 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>QoS&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Level&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Ticket priority&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Colour&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Working hours&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Colour&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Working hours&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Colour&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Working hours&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Base&lt;/td>
&lt;td>less urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yellow&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Amber&lt;/td>
&lt;td>30&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Red&lt;/td>
&lt;td>40&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>30&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>40&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>very urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>30&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>40&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>top priority&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>30&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>40&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Medium&lt;/td>
&lt;td>less urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yellow&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Amber&lt;/td>
&lt;td>30&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Red&lt;/td>
&lt;td>40&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>30&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>40&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>very urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>8&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>top priority&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>8&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Advanced&lt;/td>
&lt;td>less urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yellow&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Amber&lt;/td>
&lt;td>30&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Red&lt;/td>
&lt;td>40&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>8&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>very urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>8&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>top priority&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h3 id="algorithm-for-tickets-other-than-middleware">Algorithm for tickets other than middleware&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The priority colour changes after a dedicated amount of working hours as listed
in the table below. The priority colour calculation is running every 15 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Ticket priority&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Colour&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Working hours&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>less urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yellow&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Amber&lt;/td>
&lt;td>30&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Red&lt;/td>
&lt;td>40&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yellow&lt;/td>
&lt;td>20&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Amber&lt;/td>
&lt;td>30&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Red&lt;/td>
&lt;td>40&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>very urgent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yellow&lt;/td>
&lt;td>16&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Amber&lt;/td>
&lt;td>24&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Red&lt;/td>
&lt;td>32&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>top priority&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yellow&lt;/td>
&lt;td>12&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Amber&lt;/td>
&lt;td>18&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Red&lt;/td>
&lt;td>24&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item></channel></rss>