<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EGI Documentation – Joining the EOSC Compute Platform as a provider</title><link>/providers/getting-started/joining-eosc/</link><description>Recent content in Joining the EOSC Compute Platform as a provider on EGI Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/providers/getting-started/joining-eosc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Providers: Joining as a Federated Resource Provider - Resource Centre</title><link>/providers/getting-started/joining-eosc/federated-rp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/providers/getting-started/joining-eosc/federated-rp/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A Resource Centre (RC) is the smallest resource administration domain in the
EGI Federation. It can be either localised or geographically distributed and
provides a minimum set of local or remote IT Services compliant with
well-defined IT Capabilities (HTC, Cloud, Storage, etc.) necessary to make
resources accessible to Users. EGI is a Resource Infrastructure federating RCs
to constitute a homogeneous operational domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="registration-and-certification">Registration and certification&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In order to join the EOSC Compute platform, a RC needs to present the request
to the Research Infrastructure Provider (RP) existing in its country. A RP is
a legal organisation, part of large Resource Infrastructures like EGI,
responsible for managing and operating a number of operational services at
national level supporting RCs and user communities that contribute to such RIs.
Please have a look at the
&lt;a href="../../../operations_start_guide">Operations Start Guide&lt;/a> to get familiar with
the terms mentioned above and to have a complete picture of the several actors
participating in our landscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The RP operators are going to guide and support the RC during the registration
and certification procedures. First, the RC will be asked to read, understand,
and accept:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the &lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/document/31">“RCs Operational Level Agreement”&lt;/a>,
an agreement made between the RC and its RP that defines the minimum set of
operational services and the respective quality parameters that a Resource
Centre is required to provide in EGI;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the &lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/x/9wbSB">Security Policies&lt;/a> defined in EGI to
guarantee that all the security aspects with the service delivery are
fulfilled and enforced.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The next step is registering the RC in the EGI
&lt;a href="https://goc.egi.eu/">Configuration Database&lt;/a>: the provided information, from
the generic contacts and roles of people to the service endpoints details will
be needed to trigger the daily operations of other services and activities
provided by the EGI Infrastructure such as the Monitoring of the resources, the
Accounting, the Support, and the security activities.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>