<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EGI Documentation – Joining EGI as a provider</title><link>/providers/getting-started/joining/</link><description>Recent content in Joining EGI as a provider on EGI Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/providers/getting-started/joining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Providers: Joining as a Federated Resource Centre</title><link>/providers/getting-started/joining/federated-resource-centre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/providers/getting-started/joining/federated-resource-centre/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A Resource Centre (RC) is the smallest resource administration domain in the EGI
Federation. It can be either localised or geographically distributed and
provides a minimum set of local or remote IT Services compliant with
well-defined IT Capabilities (HTC, Cloud, Storage, etc.) necessary to make
resources accessible to Users. EGI is a Resource Infrastructure federating RCs
to constitute a homogeneous operational domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="registration-and-certification">Registration and certification&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>
Related procedure:
&lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/proc09">PROC09 Resource Centre Registration and Certification&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In order to join the EGI Infrastructure, a RC needs to present the request to
the Research Infrastructure Provider (RP) existing in its country. A RP is a
legal organisation, part of the EGI Resource Infrastructure, responsible for
managing and operating a number of operational services at national level,
supporting EGI RCs and user communities. Please have a look at the
&lt;a href="../../operations_start_guide">Operations Start Guide&lt;/a> to get familiar with the
terms mentioned above, and to have a complete picture of the several actors
participating in our landscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The RP operators are going to guide and support the RC during the registration
and certification procedures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Firstly, the RC will be asked to read, understand, and accept:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the
&lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/document/31">RCs Operational Level Agreement (OLA)&lt;/a>,
an agreement made between the RC and its RP that defines the minimum set of
operational services and the respective quality parameters that a Resource
Centre is required to provide in EGI;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the &lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/policies_procedures">Security Policies&lt;/a> defined in EGI
to guarantee that all the security aspects with the service delivery are
fulfilled and enforced.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Secondly, the RC should be registered in the EGI
&lt;a href="../../../../internal/configuration-database">Configuration Database&lt;/a>: the
provided information, from the generic contacts and roles of people to the
service endpoints details, is needed to trigger the daily operations of other
services and activities provided by the EGI Infrastructure such as the
&lt;a href="../../../../internal/monitoring">Monitoring&lt;/a> of the resources, the
&lt;a href="../../../../internal/accounting">Accounting&lt;/a>, the
&lt;a href="../../../../internal/helpdesk">Support&lt;/a>, and the
&lt;a href="../../../../internal/security-coordination">Security&lt;/a> activities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="SiteStatusFlow.png" alt="Diagram of the RCs status flow">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the entry in the Configuration Database is complete, the RP changes the RC
status from “Candidate” to “Uncertified”, and the certification procedure can
start: it comprises a
&lt;a href="../../../operations-manuals/howto04_site_certification_manual_tests">series of technical controls&lt;/a>
to verify that the provided services work according to the expectations defined
in the RC OLA. Any identified issue is notified by the RP operators to the RC
and investigated until its solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When all the certification controls are successfully passed, the RC status is
changed to “Certified” meaning that the RC is included in the EGI production
infrastructure and its resources can be consumed by the users of the
infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resource-centres-responsibilities">Resource Centres responsibilities&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="incidents-and-service-requests">Incidents and service requests&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Providing support is a fundamental part of the daily activity of a provider
participating in a large research infrastructure such as EGI. The support is not
only for the users accessing the resources but also for those who are involved
in the management and oversight of the infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As defined in the RC OLA, the RC will handle
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Incident">incidents&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Service+request">service requests&lt;/a>
registered as tickets in the &lt;a href="./../../../../internal/helpdesk">EGI Helpdesk&lt;/a>
service, with the expectation to acknowledge and process any notified issue,
within the agreed response time associated with the priority of the ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The response time is defined by the Quality of
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGISLM/Service+Level+Target+-+Quality+of+Support">Support levels&lt;/a>,
and for the RCs the level will be Medium, meaning that there will 4 priorities
for the incidents (requiring for example up to 5 working days for the “less
urgent” tickets and up to 1 working day for the “top priority” ones), while any
service request will be processed as “less urgent” ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="security-topics">Security topics&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The security posture of the infrastructure is framed by the set of policies
constituting the &lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/security-policies">Security Policies&lt;/a>. Those
policies cover different complementary activities including the operation of
services, the processing of personal data and the management of security
incidents and vulnerabilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="dealing-with-security-incidents">Dealing with security incidents&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The
&lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/security-incident-response-policy">Security Incident Response Policy&lt;/a>
aims at coordinating the incident response across the infrastructure, ensuring
that that incidents are promptly reported, and that all incidents are
investigated as fully as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Security incidents are to be treated as serious matters and their
investigation must be resourced appropriately.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Resources Centres must report suspected security incidents to their RP Security
Officer and to
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIBG/CSIRT">EGI Computer Security Incident Response Team (CSIRT)&lt;/a>
within 4 hours of discovery. This initial step will start the coordination of
the incident response as documented in the procedure
&lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/sec01">SEC01 EGI CSIRT Security Incident Handling Procedure&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This procedure has been implemented according to the Security Incident
Response Policy, to minimise the impact of security incidents affecting the
Resource Centres part of the infrastructure&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It covers guidance on how the incident response should be coordinated,
describing the responsibilities of the various parties, and encourages
post-mortem analysis and promotes cooperation between Resource Centres.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="handling-of-vulnerabilities">Handling of vulnerabilities&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The handling of vulnerabilities is a very formal process involving many
different entities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyone can report a software vulnerability via a
&lt;a href="https://csirt.egi.eu/report-vulnerability/">form&lt;/a> or by email contacting the
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIBG/SVG">Software Vulnerability Group (SVG)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The report will trigger an assessment, following the
&lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/sec02">SEC02 Software Vulnerability Issue Handling&lt;/a>
procedure, by the Software Vulnerability Group, of the risk level associated
with this vulnerability in the context of the activities of the EGI
Infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once a vulnerability has been identified as presenting a risk to the
infrastructure, it will be decided if an advisory should be prepared and
circulated to the security contacts of the sites. After an agreed period of
time, and depending on their confidentiality, advisories are made public.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vulnerabilities identified as critical are handled according to the procedure
&lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/sec03">SEC03 EGI-CSIRT Critical Vulnerability Handling&lt;/a>. When
applicable, this usually involves developing a custom
&lt;a href="https://github.com/ARGOeu/secmon-probes/">security monitoring probe&lt;/a> created to
identify on High Throughput Compute RCs if their resources are vulnerable to the
vulnerability. The status is closely monitored by the security team and
accessible to the affected RCs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using this information correlated with the one from
&lt;a href="../../../../internal/security-coordination/monitoring/pakiti">Pakiti&lt;/a>, the
patch management service collecting information about the patches deployed at
the various High Throughput Compute RCs, the Incident Response Task Force (IRTF)
on duty Security Officer will open tickets against the impacted sites according
to the &lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/wi07">WI07 Security Vulnerability Handling&lt;/a> procedure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The EGI Service Delivery and Information Security (SDIS) team of the EGI
Foundation, formerly known as the EGI Operations team, will follow up with the
resource provider to work on resolving the ticket. The first duty of the
resource provider is to acknowledge the vulnerability and then work on a prompt
resolution as suggested in the ticket. In case a satisfactory resolution is not
reached in due time, or a sign of active progress on addressing the
vulnerability is not visible, the specific Resource Centre may be suspended.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="setting-up-agreements-with-customers">Setting up agreements with customers&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once part of the production infrastructure, the RC is ready to deliver its
resources to any of the users’ communities consuming the infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here the Service Level Management (SLM) process intervenes as a matchmaker
between service expectations and needs of the user communities, acting as
customers, and the capabilities of the RCs. Customers are managed as
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Virtual+organisation">Virtual Organisations (VOs)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to select providers for provisioning services to a given customer,
technical requirements collected from the customer are used by EGI to launch a
call open to all the providers. The Expression of Interests (EoIs) collected
during the negotiation phase are used to identify the provider(s) that best
match the customer&amp;rsquo;s requirements and expectations. From a technical
perspective, several aspects will be considered during the negotiation phase
including the geographical location of the customer, national roadmap and
priority of the providers, and costs of the service provisioning in case of a
pay-for-use model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the negotiation phase ends, the selected provider(s) will:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Define a VO Operational Level Agreement(s) (OLA) with EGI Foundation for
providing the services through the EGI Portfolio to support the user
community. EGI Foundation will share with the RCs a draft of the document(s)
based on a predefined template and customised with the details of the specific
Agreement(s), such as:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the main contacts to be used for communications related to the service(s);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the duration of the Agreement;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>conditions for operating the service (service hours and exceptions);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Service Level Targets;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>if the resources are exclusively allocated or are subject to local
availability;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the payment mode;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>responsibility in case of violations and complaints;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>any limitations and constraints (if any);&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the frequency of service performance reports.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Configure the service(s) in the scope of the Agreement(s) enabling the support
of the Customer&amp;rsquo;s VO and activating the monitoring of the services/resources.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>At the same time, EGI Foundation sets up a VO Service Level Agreement (SLA) with
the given user community for the provisioning of the requested service. The EGI
VO SLA is secured with related EGI VO OLAs and is agreed on a case-by-case basis
(Fig.3).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="SLAs-Picture.png" alt="Relationship between SLA and OLA">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once approved, the Agreement is automatically renewed, as long as the
provider(s) does (do) not express a decision to terminate the Agreement at least
a month before the expiration date. In case of termination of the Agreement, the
provider must remove the support of the customer. The Agreement can also be
terminated by the customer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="managing-service-orders">Managing service orders&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Customers can request access to the services of the EOSC Compute Platform
through the EOSC Portal Marketplace. Access to the services is either fully
open, or behind service-specific authentication and authorisation steps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Depending on the nature of the service ordered, different levels of technical
support are requested to the service providers including the activation of a new
Virtual Organisation (VO), or the customization of the service with dedicated
set-up to meet the customer&amp;rsquo;s expectations. Service providers receive
notifications about services orders via
&lt;a href="https://opsportal.eosc-portal.eu/login/">SOMBO&lt;/a>, and they handle them with the
support and oversight of the EGI Foundation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="performance-reports-enforcing-olas">Performance reports: enforcing OLAs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As defined in the RCs OLA, the performance of the delivered services should meet
the Service Level Targets: the monthly performance of the RCs is monitored, and
when the targets are not achieved for three consecutive months, the affected RCs
are notified through a ticket about the OLA violation and requested to provide
within 10 working days an explanation for the low performance and a plan for
improvement.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The RCs not providing a satisfactory explanation or not replying at all are
eligible for suspension.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In order to re-join the EGI Infrastructure, any suspended RC should undergo a
new certification procedure. The “Suspended” status cannot last for more than 4
months, after which a RCs is either in production again or definitely closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Besides the Targets defined in the RCs OLA, which are enforced to guarantee the
permanence of the RC in the infrastructure, the targets promised to the users in
the VO SLAs should also be met on a monthly basis: when a violation occurs, the
RC is requested to provide a justification and a plan for improving the quality
of the provided services.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If repeated violations occur, the SLA can be renegotiated with the customer,
either by changing the Service Level Targets, or by choosing a different RCs
as a provider.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Providers: Joining as a Technology Provider</title><link>/providers/getting-started/joining/technology-provider/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/providers/getting-started/joining/technology-provider/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Technology Providers (TP) develop or deliver technology and software for
specific user communities or customisation for specific requirements. In EGI
case, they maintain the middleware which the RCs install and allowing the users
to exploit the compute, storage, data, and cloud resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="integration-of-middleware-stack">Integration of middleware stack&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To maintain an appropriate quality of service of the EGI production
infrastructure, every middleware stack (Compute, Storage, etc.) installed on and
delivered by the RCs must fulfil a number of requirements.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>
Related procedure:
&lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/proc19">PROC19 Integration of new cloud management framework or middleware stack in the EGI Infrastructure&lt;/a>)
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/proc19">PROC19&lt;/a> was defined to ensure that any single aspect
of the integration of the new piece of middleware with the infrastructure is
reviewed and assessed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the creation of the request in the
&lt;a href="../../../../internal/helpdesk">EGI Helpdesk&lt;/a>, with details about the
technology, the contacts, the expected customers, and the motivation, the
integration steps cover the following areas (where possible, steps can be done
in parallel):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://ims.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Underpinning+agreement">Underpinning Agreement&lt;/a>
(UA) between EGI Foundation and the technology provider
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>it could be either the
&lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/document/2589">Corporate-level Technology Provider Underpinning Agreement&lt;/a>
or a customised version.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Configuration Management: mapping of the new technology in the Configuration
Management Database (CMDB)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Information System: evaluating if the new technology should publish
information in the Information System according to the
&lt;a href="http://www.ogf.org/documents/GFD.147.pdf">GLUE Schema&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../../internal/monitoring">Monitoring&lt;/a>: the new technology should allow
external monitoring. If particular aspects of the technology need to be
monitored, specific monitoring probes should be provided by the TPs and
deployed on the EGI Monitoring service.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support: the Support Unit where incidents and service requests will be
addressed needs to be defined in the
&lt;a href="../../../../internal/helpdesk">EGI Helpdesk&lt;/a>, associated to the
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGISLM/Service+Level+Target+-+Quality+of+Support">Quality of Support&lt;/a>
defined in the UA.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../../../../internal/accounting">Accounting&lt;/a>: the need to gather usage data,
which depends on the technology itself and on the infrastructure requirements
and will be published in the
&lt;a href="https://accounting.egi.eu/">EGI Accounting Portal&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integration in UMD or CMD: the
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIBG/Unified+Middleware+Distribution">Unified Middleware Distribution (UMD)&lt;/a>
and
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIBG/Cloud+Middleware+Distribution">Cloud Middleware Distribution (CMD)&lt;/a>
are the integrated sets of software components contributed by Technology
Providers and packaged for deployment as production quality services in EGI.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation: exhaustive documentation for RC administrators and users should
be provided and may be added to the &lt;a href="https://docs.egi.eu/">EGI Documentation&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security: a security assessment of the software is required according to a
number of guidelines defined by the
&lt;a href="../../../../internal/security-coordination">EGI Security team&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Providers: Joining as a provider for existing EGI services</title><link>/providers/getting-started/joining/new-provider/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/providers/getting-started/joining/new-provider/</guid><description>
&lt;p>To become a provider of one of the
&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/services/research/">Services for Research&lt;/a> already included
in the EGI Portfolio, you first have to become provider of a
&lt;a href="../federated-resource-centre">federated resource centre&lt;/a>. This first step
typically requires you to become either an
&lt;a href="../../../high-throughput-compute">EGI High Throughput Compute (HTC)&lt;/a> provider,
by deploying Compute and Storage capabilities, or a Cloud service provider, by
deploying OpenStack and federating it into the
&lt;a href="../../../cloud-compute">EGI Cloud Compute&lt;/a> service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once such a foundational role is fulfilled you can configure/deploy the
additional service within your resource centre.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Providers: Joining as a provider of a Core Service</title><link>/providers/getting-started/joining/core-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/providers/getting-started/joining/core-service/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>With the term &amp;ldquo;Central&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Core&amp;rdquo; Service we refer to a category of services
in the EGI Infrastructure providing capabilities that support and complement
the other services of the infrastructure and the related activities. A list of
those services is available in the section
&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/services/federation/">Services for Federation&lt;/a> of our
site.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The EGI Core Services are co-funded by EGI Foundation and the providers are
selected through a bidding process: the technical details of the services that
should be delivered are advertised to the
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIG/EGI+Council">EGI Council&lt;/a>, and only
the providers with the
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIG/EGI+Participant">EGI Participant&lt;/a> role
in the Council can apply to the bid.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/join-the-egi-federation/">How to join the EGI Federation&lt;/a>
as a member of the Council.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/egi-federation/#council">Current members&lt;/a> of the EGI
Council&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Differently from services with a distributed nature such as HTC, Cloud, and
Storage, they cannot be ordered through the Marketplace, but they become
available as soon as a user joins the infrastructure (e.g., the access to the
&lt;a href="../../../../internal/helpdesk">EGI Helpdesk&lt;/a> service).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="selection-of-the-providers-and-registration">Selection of the providers and registration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With the selected providers, EGI Foundation negotiates and signs an
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Operational+Level+Agreement">OLA&lt;/a>
defining the terms and conditions for the delivery of the services; at the same
time, the process to add the services to the
&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/services/">EGI Service portfolio&lt;/a> is started, if the service
is not already included.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point, steps, similar to the ones for
&lt;a href="../federated-resource-centre">Resource Centers&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="../technology-provider">Technology Providers&lt;/a>, follow in order to guarantee the
regular day-to-day operation of the service, such as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>registration in the
&lt;a href="../../../../internal/configuration-database">Configuration Database&lt;/a> and
certification;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>definition of the Support Unit in the
&lt;a href="../../../../internal/helpdesk">Helpdesk&lt;/a> system to handle incidents and
service requests;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>enabling of the monitoring;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>periodic performance reports as defined in the given OLA to verify that the
Service Level Targets are achieved.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In addition to this, the providers are also requested to create a
&lt;a href="#capacity-plan">capacity plan&lt;/a>, an
&lt;a href="#availability-and-continuity-plan">availability and continuity plan&lt;/a>, and to
interact with &lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/chm">Change Management (CHM)&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/rdm">Release and Deployment Management (RDM)&lt;/a> processes for
&lt;a href="#managing-changes-and-new-releases">managing changes and new releases&lt;/a> of their
services.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="capacity-plan">Capacity plan&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The capacity plan is important to assess if the capacity of the service is
sufficient to respond to the current and to the future demand of the service.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Any capacity aspect of the service delivery is analysed (human, technical, and
financial) with the definition of quantitative parameters to measure the usage
and the load of the service. The approach to adjust the capacity of the service
in relation to a change in the demand is defined, and recommendations on
capacity requirements for the next reporting period are provided as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>EGI Foundation defined a template for the Capacity plans and contacts and
supports the service providers for the creation of a new Capacity plan or for
their regular reviews (the reviews are usually performed at least twice per
year).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="availability-and-continuity-plan">Availability and continuity plan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the Availability and Continuity plan, a number of risks affecting the
availability and continuity of the service is identified and assessed: each risk
is rated in terms of likelihood and impact with the definition of
countermeasures to implement that should avoid the occurrence of the given risk.
Any remaining vulnerability is identified as well, and in case the rating of a
risk is considered to be too high in relation to the risk acceptance criteria, a
plan either to improve the existing countermeasures or to implement new ones is
created, with the aim either to reduce the likelihood of a risk or to mitigate
the impact in case a risk occurs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The plan is completed by a continuity and recovery test, where the continuity of
the service and its recovery capacity are tested against a simulated disruption
scenario: the performance of this test is useful to spot any issue in the
recovery procedures of the service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also in this case, the discussion of the Availability and Continuity plan is
started and overseen by EGI Foundation who shares with the providers a template
that will be filled in with the details of the given service. Availability and
Continuity plans are reviewed on a yearly basis.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="managing-changes-and-new-releases">Managing changes and new releases&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>All changes to the services should follow the EGI Change Management (CHM)
process according to the &lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/chm-policy">Change Policy&lt;/a>, in
order to evaluate the potential impact that a change can have on the service
and on the infrastructure as a whole.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When registering a
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Request+For+Change">Request for Change&lt;/a>,
besides a general description of the change, the providers are expected to
provide:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the risk level as a result of assessing the impact and the likelihood of
things going wrong,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the type of change,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the eventual list of other services potentially affected by the change,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>if it is possible to revert the change,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the proposed date for the implementation of the change,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>if it is needed to schedule a downtime of the service.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Requests for Changes are assessed by the Change Advisory Board (CAB), deciding
whether the Change is going to be approved or rejected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For recurrent changes with a relatively low risk level, the providers can
request to classify them as Standard Changes, so that invoking the CAB won’t be
necessary and they can undergo the release process after the release plan is
agreed with the EGI CHM staff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Emergency Changes are created when there is an urgent need to fix either a
newly discovered security vulnerability or a critical issue: in this case the
formal approval of the CAB is not required, and it is enough that the release
plan is accepted by CHM staff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In all of the other situations the changes are classified as Normal and
depending on their risk level they might need to be assessed by the CAB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before the release in the production environment, the providers may invite the
users or other impacted service providers, to test the new changes on a
pre-production instance in order to gather feedback and to find out possible
issues that might be overlooked during the preparation of the new release. If no
problems are found, the release can go live, and a Post Implementation Review is
conducted after a few days to close the case.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="security-aspects">Security aspects&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The providers of central services are subject to the same policies, procedures
and requirements applying to the federated service providers, as documented at
&lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/policies-procedures-internal-service-providers">this page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nevertheless, they are also subject to the following requirement that is
documented in the service OLA that is being agreed with them:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>They should immediately report suspected security incidents to the EGI
Foundation. This is not exempting them to follow the
&lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/sec01">SEC01 EGI CSIRT Security Incident Handling Procedure&lt;/a>
and inform EGI CSIRT within 4 hours.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also important to understand that when processing of personal data is
taking place, EGI Foundation holds the role of Data Controller and the provider
is a Data Processor, as defined in the
&lt;a href="https://gdpr.eu/article-4-definitions/">Global Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Data Processing Agreements, regulating the conditions and constraints of the
data processing activities conducted by the Data Processor on behalf of the
Data controller, will be put in place on the initiative of the EGI Foundation
staff.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>EGI Foundation will also prepare, together with the service provider, adequate
Privacy Notice and Acceptable Use policy that have to be presented and made
available to the users of the service.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>EGI Foundation is also complying with all the principles set out by the REFEDS
Data Protection Code of Conduct in its most
&lt;a href="https://wiki.refeds.org/display/CODE/Data+Protection+Code+of+Conduct+Home">recent version&lt;/a>,
implying that the central service provider should also comply with them.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The central service provider should also follow requirements relating to the
software and covering the usage of a proper licence, the access to and
management of the source code, implementation of best practices; as well as
requirements relating to the IT Service management and covering the need for
having key staff properly trained about IT Service Management, committing to
continual improvement and having their
&lt;a href="https://confluence.egi.eu/display/EGIG/Service+management+system">Service Management System (SMS)&lt;/a>
interfacing with the EGI SMS, especially for important processes like the Change
Management process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Providers: Introducing a new EGI service</title><link>/providers/getting-started/joining/new-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/providers/getting-started/joining/new-service/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The EGI services are contributed by the
&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/egi-federation/#council">EGI Council members&lt;/a>, who can
propose new services through the
&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/publication/egi-federation-service-strategy-2022-2024/">EGI Service Strategy&lt;/a>,
that defines the overall direction to EGI services for a few years time window.
The services are designed, validated with the EGI Community, and with the help
of the &lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/ssb">EGI Services and Solutions Board (SSB)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The evolution of the services is driven by 5 Strategic Objectives (SO) which are
based on the knowledge of the user community needs that are being gathered
through research and innovation projects, customer interviews and analysis of
trends. Each defines an area for possible future work, and if approved, can be
developed into more concrete goals and intended results.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>SO1: Federated compute continuum&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SO2: Federated Data Lakes and repositories&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SO3: Data analytics and scientific tools including AI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SO4: Professional support and consultancy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SO5: Investigation of a trusted compute platform for sensitive data processing&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you want to propose a new service, you should approach your national EGI
Council member, or fallback to the &lt;a href="https://go.egi.eu/ssb">EGI SSB&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>