<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EGI Documentation – Helpdesk</title><link>/internal/helpdesk/</link><description>Recent content in Helpdesk on EGI Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/internal/helpdesk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Internal: Account and privileges</title><link>/internal/helpdesk/account-and-privileges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/internal/helpdesk/account-and-privileges/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="managing-ggus-account-data">Managing GGUS account data&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>GGUS users should be able to manage their GGUS account data by themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Information about registration and account management is collected on
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=register_info">GGUS registration page&lt;/a> and could be
reached by clicking the &amp;ldquo;Registration&amp;rdquo; link on top of
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/">GGUS home page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For managing the GGUS account data the user has to click the link “Check your
GGUS account” at the bottom of this page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="updating-the-personal-certificate-information">Updating the personal certificate information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Users should update their certificate information before their old certificate
expires. They can navigate to the
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=register_info">registration page&lt;/a>, click the link &amp;ldquo;Check
your GGUS account&amp;rdquo; and update their data. Modifying the DN field will result in
an additional DN field: the old DN will be kept and the new DN will be added.
Subsequently, the user is identified with the two DNs. If the old DN is no more
valid please just clear the DN field and save the change. Once the old
certificate has expired before updating the account data, users can request an
update via GGUS ticket against Helpdesk(GGUS) support unit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="linking-the-egi-sso-persistent-id-to-the-ggus-account">Linking the EGI SSO persistent ID to the GGUS account&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pre-requisites: the email address of your EGI SSO account must be equal to the
email address registered in GGUS!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For adding your EGI SSO persistent ID to your account data please do the
following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>login to GGUS using your EGI SSO account&lt;/li>
&lt;li>on GGUS home click the &lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=register_info">Registration&lt;/a>
link&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_EGI_AAI_1.png" alt="your account information">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>click the button &amp;ldquo;Add my Shibboleth ID to my account&amp;rdquo; at the bottom of the
yellow box.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="getting-supporter-privileges">Getting supporter privileges&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In order to process tickets assigned to the support unit you belong to, or in
general tickets submitted by other users and assigned to other support units,
you need to own supporter privileges. Therefore users need to register an
account at GGUS. Registration can be done either using an X509 personal
certificate or using the EGI AAI account.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="registration-with-an-x509-certificate">Registration with an x509 certificate&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For registering with an X509 certificate the user should go to
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/index.php?mode=index">GGUS home&lt;/a> and click the
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=register_info">registration link&lt;/a> in the menu bar at the
left. This link opens the registration information page which gives some
additional information about registration process. Clicking on the
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=register_info">registration link&lt;/a> guides to the form that
the user has to fill in. After filling in the registration form, GGUS team will
check whether support privileges can be granted. The user will receive an email
from the GGUS team (usually) confirming their supporter privileges.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="registration-with-the-egi-aai-account">Registration with the EGI AAI account&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Users who do not have a valid X509 certificate can access GGUS via
&lt;a href="../../../users/check-in">EGI Check-in&lt;/a>. For getting support privileges the user
needs to be member of the
&lt;a href="https://aai.egi.eu/registry/co_petitions/start/coef:69">ggus-supporters&lt;/a> group
in EGI Check-in. However the user should fill in the
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=register_info">registration form&lt;/a> for creating an account
at GGUS. Support privileges will be granted automatically. The user will receive
an automated email from GGUS system confirming their support privileges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Registration_Form.png" alt="GGUS registration form">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both authentication methods, X509 certificate and EGI Check-in account, will be
guaranteed in the future. Since the use of login and password will no longer be
guaranteed in the future, it is recommended to access GGUS with a valid digital
certificate or EGI Check-in.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="troubleshooting">Troubleshooting&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="im-member-of-ggus-supportersegieu-group-why-dont-i-have-support-privileges-in-ggus">I&amp;rsquo;m member of ggus-supporters.egi.eu group. Why don&amp;rsquo;t I have support privileges in GGUS?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pre-requisites: the email address of your EGI SSO account must be equal to the
email address registered in GGUS!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Case 1: user isn&amp;rsquo;t registered in GGUS yet.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Unregistered users have to register first. On
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/?mode=register_info">registration page&lt;/a> you will see this text:
“You are member of EGI AAI CheckIn ggus supporter. You will get automatically
support right for the GGUS portal once you will submit this form.“ Support
permissions will be granted automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Account_Update_PersistentID.png" alt="Updating PersistentID">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on the &amp;ldquo;Add my &amp;hellip;.&amp;rdquo; button.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Case 2: user already registered in GGUS with an X509 DN.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>You can decide to add the Shibboleth ID to the existing account and check the
updated account. In case the email addresses are different you may either
harmonize your email address in EGI SSO and GGUS account or create a new account
using EGI SSO data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-in-touch-wit-the-ggus-team">Getting in touch wit the GGUS team?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The preferred way to get in contact with the GGUS team is by submitting a GGUS
ticket against Helpdesk (GGUS) support unit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="additional-information">Additional information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-User_Guide">GGUS user guide&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Short-Guide">GGUS short guide&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Support-Staff-Guide">GGUS support staff guide&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Internal: GGUS Support Staff Guide</title><link>/internal/helpdesk/ggus-support-staff-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/internal/helpdesk/ggus-support-staff-guide/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="whats-new-in-the-latest-release">What’s new in the latest release?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please see the &lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/index.php?mode=release_notes">Ongoing work list&lt;/a>
for further information.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="access-to-ggus">Access to GGUS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>GGUS is reachable via &lt;a href="https://helpdesk.egi.eu/">https://helpdesk.egi.eu/&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://ggus.eu">https://ggus.eu&lt;/a> using a web
browser. Another way for accessing GGUS is using the direct link provided in
the notification emails sent after ticket updates. However either a valid X509
personal certificate or a Check-in account are required for accessing the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="features-of-ggus">Features of GGUS&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="ggus-home">GGUS Home&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>GGUS home provides a quick overview over tickets submitted by the current user,
the latest tickets of other users and a collection of news and links to useful
information. The navigation bar is located on the left side of GGUS pages. It
provides links to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Did you know?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Registration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>My dashboard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Search Engine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Submit form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support staff pages&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GGUS Home&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Legals&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contact form&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="did-you-know">Did you know&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After each release, a major change or new feature is explained in some
sentences here.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="documentation">Documentation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the documentation section there is a collection of links providing useful
information around GGUS system.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="registration">Registration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>All information about registration can be found on the
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/index.php?mode=register_info">registration page&lt;/a>. For
registering as support staff, click the link “Apply” and fill in the registration
form. After registering successfully you will receive a confirmation mail from
GGUS team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to update your account data, you can do this using the link &amp;ldquo;Check
your GGUS account&amp;rdquo; on the registration page. If you can’t access GGUS web
interface due to changed DN string of your personal certificate, you can log into
the system using your Check-in account. Then go to the registration page and
click on Check/update your GGUS account. The system shows you all your user data.
It detects the new DN string of your browser automatically. Just save the changes
by clicking on button Update now. Additional information on GGUS accounts is
available here(link to new location of &lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Account)">https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Account)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="support-staff-page">Support staff page&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Access to the support staff page is restricted to users having support privileges
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Support-Privileges">https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Support-Privileges&lt;/a> . Depending on further
privileges people may have there are links to e.g. news administration and other
features. All support staffs can use the GGUS report generator and the GGUS
ticket timeline tool as well as links to other information useful for support
staffs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Support_Staff.png" alt="GGUS Support Staff">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ggus-ticket-timeline-tool">GGUS ticket timeline tool&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The link to the GGUS ticket timeline tool is located on support staff page. The
ticket timeline tool provides a graphical overview of tickets concerning a selected
site and time range. It shows all tickets that have been updated during the
selected time range. When moving the mouse over one of the colored bars some
additional information is displayed. Clicking on the ticket ID opens a new window
showing the ticket details and the modify section of the ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_TTT.png" alt="GGUS ticket timeline tool">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ggus-report-generator">GGUS Report Generator&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The link to the GGUS Report Generator is located on support staff page and on GGUS
home page in section &amp;ldquo;GGUS tools/reports&amp;rdquo;. The GGUS Report Generator could be used
for generating statistics and reports for all support units in GGUS. Further
information on the report generator is available on the
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_Report_Generator_(GGUS)">https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_Report_Generator_(GGUS)&lt;/a> .&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="submit-form">Submit form&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Depending on the user&amp;rsquo;s privileges GGUS offers different ticket submit forms:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>common user ticket&lt;/li>
&lt;li>team ticket&lt;/li>
&lt;li>alarm ticket&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CMS ticket (for members of CMS VO)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>notify multiple sites which is a bulk submit for addressing multiple sites about
the same issue.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="ticket-categories-and-ticket-types">Ticket categories and ticket types&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>GGUS offers two fields which help to classify various tickets into categories
and types.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="ticket-categories">Ticket categories&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>The ticket category is for differentiating between issues and service requests.
This distinction is helpful for supporters as well as for the GGUS reporting, e.g.
for excluding test tickets. The ticket category field offers four different values:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Incident (for issues),&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change Request (for service requests)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Test&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When submitting a ticket the ticket category field is not visible. It defaults to
“Incident” and is only editable for supporters, not for users. So it is up to the
supporter to check and, if necessary, classify the ticket correctly. Please see
details in section Changing ticket category.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="ticket-types">Ticket types&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>The ticket type field is for differentiating between standard user tickets and
tickets for achieving the special requirements of various groups like the LHC VOs or
EGI operations. It can’t be set manually, but is set automatically by the system
based on several rules. The ticket type field could not be changed during ticket
lifetime. Possible ticket types in GGUS are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>USER&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TEAM,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ALARM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>OPS.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h6 id="user-tickets">USER tickets&lt;/h6>
&lt;p>The ticket type USER is the default ticket type. User tickets are the usual tickets
which can be submitted by everyone. They are visible to everybody. They can be
updated either by the submitter himself or by any supporter.&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="team-tickets">TEAM tickets&lt;/h6>
&lt;p>The purpose of TEAM tickets is to allow a group of people to submit and modify
ticketseditable by the whole group. TEAM tickets can only be submitted by people
who have the appropriate permissions in the GGUS user database. These people belong
to either one of the four LHC VOs (ALICE, ATLAS, CMS, LHCB) or to the BIOMED or
BELLE VO and are nominated by the particular VO management. TEAM tickets are editable
by all members of the VO team (which are the so called VO shifters) regardless own
the ticket. TEAM tickets are visible to everyone. They can be submitted for all tier-1
sites in EGI and are routed to the appropriate NGI/ROC automatically, bypassing the
TPM. Additionally the site is notified by mail about the ticket. By default TEAM
tickets are routed to the appropriate NGI/ROC directly, bypassing TPM. But the
submitter could also choose to route it to the TPM instead. Further information on
TEAM tickets is available in the TEAM tickets FAQs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="alarm-tickets">ALARM tickets&lt;/h6>
&lt;p>The purpose of ALARM tickets is to notify tier-1 administrators about serious problems
of the site at any time, independent from usual office hours. They can only be submitted
by experts who have the appropriate permissions in the GGUS user database. These people
belong to one of the four LHC VOs (ALICE, ATLAS, CMS, LHCB) and are nominated by the
particular VO management. They are about 3 to 4 people per VO. ALARM tickets are editable
by all members of the VO team (which are the so called VO shifters) regardless they own
the ticket. They are visible to everyone. ALARM tickets can be submitted for all tier-1
sites in EGI and are routed to the appropriate NGI/ROC automatically, bypassing the TPM.
Additionally the tier-1 site is notified by an ALARM email. It is up to the tier-1 site
how to deal with this ALARM email. Further information on TEAM tickets is available in
the ALARM tickets FAQs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="ops-tickets">OPS tickets&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>This ticket type is used for operations tickets submitted via the operations portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="my-dashboard">My dashboard&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This dashboard can be used for getting quick access to any ticket of interest. Each
ticket has to be added manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="search-engine">Search Engine&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The search engine provides a large number of fields for creating dedicated query
strings. Many of them have additional information hidden behind a question mark icon.
The results of a query are shown in a results list. The default search displays all
open tickets of last week. They were ordered by date of creation in descending manor.
For further details on using the search engine see chapter Searching for tickets.
The result list is showing a color schema reflecting the priority of tickets. The
algorithm used for setting the priority colours is explained in chapter Reminder emails.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="searching-for-tickets">Searching for tickets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Various possibilities of searching tickets in GGUS are described in this FAQ. Please
avoid searching for “all” tickets or “solved” tickets without any time-frame if not
necessary for some reasons as these searches cause heavy load on the machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="searching-via-ticket-id">Searching via Ticket ID&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Searching via ticket ID is the easiest and fastest way to look at a ticket. When searching
via Ticket ID all other search parameters are ignored. Besides searching for all open
tickets this is the recommended kind of search, because it avoids needless workload on the
system. When searching via ticket ID the ticket details are shown in the same window. For
getting back to the main page use the “Back” button of your browser. For Firefox users there
is a nice add-on for adding a customized search for any web page to the browser&amp;rsquo;s search bar
available &lt;a href="https://firefox.maltekraus.de/extensions/add-to-search-bar">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="searching-via-parameters">Searching via parameters&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The search parameters can be combined in any way wanted. Description fields “Keyword”,
“Involved supporter” and “Assigned to person” trigger a LIKE search to the database.
Concatenating keywords with “AND” or “OR” is currently not possible. The result of a search
by parameters is shown in the result list. For viewing ticket details just click on the ID.
A new window opens showing ticket details. For getting back to the search result just close
the window with the ticket details.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="customizing-result-list">Customizing result list&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can customize the result list in various ways. One way to customize the result list is
by checking or un-checking the appropriate boxes in the blue bar. The related columns will
then be added or removed. Another way for customizing the result list is by selecting
another ticket order in field Order tickets by. After changing the result list layout you
have to refresh the search result by clicking the Go! button.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="exporting-search-results">Exporting search results&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Search results can be exported in csv or xml format for further processing. After clicking
on the appropriate link a new window opens showing the results in the specified format.
Out of this window you can save a local copy of this file.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ticket-data">Ticket data&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>By clicking on the ticket ID of a ticket in the results list of the search engine you can
access the ticket data. The ticket data is divided into 3 main sections:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ticket information&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ticket history&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ticket modify section&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="ticket-information">Ticket information&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The system shows the information section after clicking on a ticket ID.It provides an
overview of all relevant ticket parameters and could be divided into 5 areas:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>submitter data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>issue data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ticket data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>description&lt;/li>
&lt;li>solution&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Additional features of the ticket information section are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>export of ticket information data,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>escalate button,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>duplicate ticket and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>convert team to alarm.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Info_Support.png" alt="Ticket information">&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="duplicate-ticket">Duplicate ticket&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Figure 5: Ticket duplication
Supporters have the opportunity to duplicate an existing ticket up to 15 times.
The duplicate feature is located right below ticket information. It is useful if
a ticket concerns not only one support unit but has to be handled by several
support units. The fields that are copied into the duplicated tickets are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Internal Diary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Login&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Last Modifier&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Submitter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Subject&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Duplicate.png" alt="Ticket duplication">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Attachments are not duplicated physically but linked to all duplicated tickets.
The Responsible Unit is set to &amp;ldquo;TPM&amp;rdquo; by default.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="convert-team-tickets-to-alarm-tickets">Convert TEAM tickets to ALARM tickets&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Figure 3: Convert team to alarm ticket
Support staffs with ALARM privileges are able to convert TEAM tickets to ALARM
tickets clicking on a button in the ticket information section. This feature is
only available for the WLCG VOs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Convert_Alarm.png" alt="Convert team to alarm ticket">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ticket-history">Ticket history&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The ticket history is located below ticket information. It shows all relevant
changes of the ticket in chronological manner. Changes of these fields lead to
a new entry in ticket history:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Assign ticket to support unit&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Assign ticket to one person&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Affected Site&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Public Diary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change ticket category&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change status&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change VO&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change priority&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Involve others&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Type of issue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Internal Diary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Solution&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Related issue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>VO specific&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For making the history more readable solution entries and entries in the public
diary are marked with green colour, entries of the internal diary with orange
colour.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ticket-modify-section">Ticket modify section&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Figure 6: Ticket modify section
The ticket modification area offers several fields for modifying a ticket. The
fields are described in detail below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Modifysection_Support.png" alt="Ticket modify section">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Assign ticket to support unit is showing all support units involved in GGUS.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Assign ticket to specific person(s) allows assigning tickets to a dedicated
person within the current support unit. If a mail address is typed in the
system generates an email to inform the recipient about the ticket assignment.
The length is limited to 254 characters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change status is a drop-down-list with all possible status values.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change VO is a drop-down-list with all possible VO values.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Type of issue provides a drop-down-list of possible issue types.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change priority provides a drop-down-list of possible priority values.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Notify site is for specifying the site affected by the issue. For ticket
types “ALARM” and “TEAM” this field is not editable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change ticket category provides a drop-down list with values “Incident”,
“Change Request”, “Documentation” and &amp;ldquo;Test&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Involve others allows contacting any people who may help to solve an issue.
Several mail addresses can be typed in separated by “;”. The length is limited
to 254 characters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>VO specific is a flag indicating whether a issue is VO specific or not.
Default is “no”.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change CC recipient is for editing the mail addresses specified during ticket
submit for notifying any person about a ticket.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MoU Area can only be set for tickets of type “TEAM” or “ALARM”. Possible
values are documented here.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Subject is for editing the subject of a ticket.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Internal Diary can be used for internal remarks. It is only shown to people
with support privileges and limited to 4000 characters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Public Diary updates always trigger an update mail to the submitter. It is
limited to 4000 characters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click here to insert… expands the solution field.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Solution can be up to 4000 characters. It is used for explaining the solution.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hide solution hides the solution field.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reminders feature can be set to “Please send reminder on” if status is changed
to “on hold” or “waiting for reply”. In this case a date can be selected on
which a reminder mail was sent. This feature should help supporters not to forget
tickets which were not worked on for a longer time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Related issue can be used to reference any URL. It is limited to 125 characters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click here to expand … expands the ticket relation section.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hide ticket relation section hides ticket relation fields.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mark this ticket as Master is described in detail in chapter Master-Slave
relations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mark this ticket as Slave is described in detail in chapter Master-Slave
relations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mark this ticket as child this feature is described in detail in chapter
Parent-Child relations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cross reference is for referencing as much other GGUS tickets as necessary. For
each ticket referenced here a symmetric link is added to the referenced ticket
automatically.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Want to upload attachment? is for adding attachments. Only one attachment can
be added at a time. The total number of attachments is unlimited.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="ticket-participation">Ticket Participation&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>GGUS system offers various possibilities for participating in tickets. They are&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the CC field,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the Involve others field and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the Subscribe field.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>An overview on these fields is given in the table below. Ticket participation
can be done by adding a valid mail address to one of these fields. Please avoid
adding closed mailing lists as such produce a lot of mail errors! Several mail
addresses have to be separated by semicolon.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>User submit&lt;/th>
&lt;th>User modify&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Supporter modify&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>CC&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yes&lt;/td>
&lt;td>No&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yes&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Involve others&lt;/td>
&lt;td>No&lt;/td>
&lt;td>No&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yes&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Subscribe&lt;/td>
&lt;td>No&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yes&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yes&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="the-cc-field">The “CC” field&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>The CC field can be set by the user in the ticket submit form. Updates are only
possible for supporters for correcting or removing invalid mail addresses. Every
ticket update triggers a notification email to the mail address specified in the
“CC” field.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="the-involve-others-field">The “Involve others” field&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>The “Involve others” field is only for supporters use. Every ticket update
triggers a notification email to the mail address specified in the “Involve
others” field.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="subscribe-to-this-ticket-field">Subscribe to this ticket field&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>This field can be used by any user for participating in tickets at any time.
The user has just to add his mail address. He will receive notifications for
updates of the public diary or the solution for following the whole ticket life
cycle. &amp;ldquo;Internal Diary&amp;rdquo; entries never go to the people who subscribed to a ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="master-slave-relations">Master-Slave relations&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Several tickets describing the same issue can be put into a master-slave relation.
One of them can be marked as master, the other ones as slave. Only the master
ticket has to be dealt with. The slave tickets are set to “on hold”. They can’t
be updated directly as long as they are in a master-slave relation. The user gets
an automated notification if a ticket is marked as slave. All updates of the
master were pushed to the slaves. When solving the master the slaves are solved to.
The master-slave relation is kept after the master is solved. Nevertheless each
ticket can be reopened separately. Updates on reopened slave tickets are possible.
A master-slave relation can be reset manually either by removing the master ID of
a slave ticket or by un-checking the master checkbox of the master. If a master is
unmarked as master all slaves were reset to “standard” tickets automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="selecting-slave-tickets">Selecting slave tickets&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Marking a ticket as slave is only possible if there is already a master ticket.
If a ticket is marked as slave a popup window opens showing available master
tickets. For selecting a master just click on the ID. The master ID
is set automatically. Once you have chosen a wrong master ID click Reset
Master-Slave relation and select another one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Select_Master.png" alt="Select master ID">&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="showing-a-masters-slave-tickets">Showing a master’s slave tickets&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>To show all related slave tickets click on link “show slaves for this ticket”.
A popup window opens showing the IDs of all slave tickets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Ticket_Relation.png" alt="Ticket relation section">&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="searching-for-masterslave-tickets">Searching for master/slave tickets&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>If you want to search for master or slave tickets you can do this using field
“Special attributes” of the search engine. The status value for searching is
set to an appropriate value accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="parent-child-relations">Parent-child relations&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Parent-child relationships work in reverse to master-slave relationships. The
parent ticket cannot be resolved until all of its child tickets are resolved.
The parent ticket is set to the status &amp;ldquo;on hold&amp;rdquo; while the child tickets are
waiting for their solution. For each solved child ticket a note is added to
the parent ticket history including the solution of the child ticket. After
the last open child ticket has been solved the status of the parent ticket
changes to “in progress” automatically. In addition, the system sends a
notification mail to the responsible support unit that all child tickets have
been solved now. So the parent ticket can be “solved” too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="selecting-child-tickets">Selecting child tickets&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>A ticket can be selected as child ticket by checking the box “Mark this ticket
as child of ticket” and adding the ticket ID of the parent ticket. A comment is
added to the ticket history automatically stating “This ticket is a child
ticket of GGUS ticket # 18492”. Multiple child tickets can be related to one
parent ticket by repeating this procedure. The parent ticket is flagged as
“parent” automatically. A comment is added to the ticket history automatically
stating “This ticket is a parent ticket. It has to wait the solving of all its
child tickets. GGUS ticket #18493 is a child to this ticket.&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="resetting-child-tickets">Resetting child tickets&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>For resetting child tickets just remove the tick from the check box “Mark this
ticket as child of ticket”.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="selecting-parent-tickets">Selecting parent tickets&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>Selecting a parent ticket explicitly is not possible. The parent tickets are
flagged automatically by the system while the parent ID is specified for a
child ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="searching-for-parentchild-tickets">Searching for parent/child tickets&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>The search for parent or child tickets is similar to the search for master or
slave tickets. It can be done using field “Special attributes” of the search
engine.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="working-on-tickets">Working on tickets&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This section is a description of how the GGUS ticketing system behaves. There
are other documents which describe the system in more detail and include more
of the implementation details. One of the most important fields of the system
is the status field. Many workflows are triggered by status value changes.
Please read the Short Guide for getting information on status values. Tickets
are normally assigned to a support unit. This means that the ticket notification
is sent to a mailing list composed of many supporters. One of these supporters
assigns the ticket to himself and takes responsibility for it; the supporter
changes the status to “in progress”. This person is then in charge of the ticket.
He either solves it or reassigns the ticket to somebody else. The status of the
ticket stays set to “in progress” if the ticket is under the responsibility of
one supporter and until the ticket has been solved.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="user-ticketing-work-flow">User ticketing work flow&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A graphical view of the ticket flow in GGUS is shown here:
&lt;img src="GGUS_Status_Values.png" alt="GGUS ticket flow">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The GGUS Support is organized with two main lines of support:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>First line of support gets immediate notification of tickets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Second line of support is only notified of tickets by the first line of
support.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The first line support is provided by an organisation called TPM – Ticket
Processing Manager. The TPM team has members who have very good general grid
knowledge. It is an organisation populated by people provided from the Czech NGI.
This organisation is responsible for the routing and processing of all active
tickets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second line support is formed by many support units. Each support unit is
formed from members who are specialists in various areas of grid middleware, or
NGI/ROC supporters for operations problems, or VO specific supporters. The
membership of the support units is maintained on mailing lists.
If the user responds to any e-mail received from GGUS, then the reply is added
to the ticket history. The subject of the email includes meta data to ensure the
association of the response with the ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tickets-waiting-for-user-input">Tickets waiting for user input&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The workflows for tickets waiting for user input is described in this FAQ.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="advice-for-tpms">Advice for TPMs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The following advice is intended for people working on TPM.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Change support unit to “TPM” if you are working on a ticket&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Just typing a comment into solution field does NOT cause an email to the
user automatically. Only changing status to “solved” causes an automatic mail.
If you want to contact the user you can do this using the “Public Diary”.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change status to “waiting for reply” while waiting for the user&amp;rsquo;s reply.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Be careful when using the field “Assign ticket to one person”. Please avoid
using mailing list names, or the mail list address of a remote help-desk system.
With a mailing list, the mail may not reach the recipient because many mailing
lists are closed lists and will not accept the message. Sending mail to a remote
help-desk system can confuse the remote system and lead to trouble.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Change the ticket category if you think the ticket is not dealing with an
incident but describing a service request like a documentation update, adding
someone to a mailing list and so on. See chapter Changing ticket category for
details.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="changing-ticket-category">Changing ticket category&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When submitting a ticket the ticket category field could not be set but default
to “Incident”. It is up to the supporters to decide whether a ticket describes
an “Incident” or a service ticket. Service tickets are tickets that request
something be done like:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>adding someone to a mailing list&lt;/li>
&lt;li>updating documentation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>providing more space for storing data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>They do not report issues. This differentiation is compliant to ITIL.
Differentiating between incident tickets and service tickets can help supporters
to order tickets they are responsible for by urgency. The GGUS reporting also
relies on the correct setting of the ticket category field as it does ignore
tickets of category &amp;ldquo;Test&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="forwarding-a-ticket-to-another-unit">Forwarding a ticket to another unit&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Tickets assigned to a support unit by error or tickets that need actions from
other support units should be either assigned back to the TPM or assigned to the
relevant support unit directly. In both cases an explanation in the public diary
will avoid confusion.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="solving-a-ticket">Solving a ticket&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this section the usage of the different status values and input fields is described.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The system offers two groups of meta states, open states and terminal states.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="open-states">Open states&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>new: this is the default status for submitted tickets. It is set by the system
and can’t be selected in the drop-down list menu.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>assigned: this status is set automatically and can&amp;rsquo;t be selected in the drop-down
list menu. After a ticket is assigned to a support unit, this unit is informed via
e-mail about the ticket assignment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>in progress: support staff who work on the ticket should change status to
“in progress”. This is necessary to announce that somebody is taking care of this
ticket and is working on it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>waiting for reply: This status value should be set ONLY by the supporter and ONLY
when asking the SUBMITTER for further information. The supporter can decide whether
(s)he wants to be notified about this ticket by the system. (S)he can choose any date
in the future (s)he wants to be notified and select the radio button &amp;ldquo;Please send
reminder on&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>on hold: some tickets are not solvable while needing a software patch or something
similar for example. The reasons should be explained in field “Public Diary”.
Additionally a hint in field “Related issue” may be useful. The supporter can decide
whether he wants to be notified about this ticket by the system. He can choose any date
in the future he wants to be notified and select the radio button “Please send reminder
on”.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>reopened: normally this status value is set by the user, if he is not happy with the
provided solution. It can also be used by supporters if a better solution is found for
a ticket already solved. In this case status should be set to “reopened”, new solution
put in and status changed to “solved” again. Leaving status as “solved” and just putting
in the new solution does not cause an automatic solution mail to the user.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="terminal-states">Terminal states&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>solved: If a solution is found and put into the Solution field, status has to be set
to &amp;ldquo;solved&amp;rdquo;. Only on status change to &amp;ldquo;solved&amp;rdquo; the user receives a solution mail
automatically. Please put a full explanation in Solution field of how the issue was
solved. You can use qualification terms like:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>fixed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fixed (work around)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>works as designed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>other&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>unsolved: This status is for tickets that can not be solved due to any reason. Please
add a comment in the solution field explaining why it can&amp;rsquo;t be solved. You can use
qualification terms like:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>duplicate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>invalid&lt;/li>
&lt;li>wont fix&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>verified: This status can only be set by the ticket submitter. TEAM tickets, by design,
can be &amp;lsquo;verified&amp;rsquo; by all TEAMers in the VO. ALARM tickets can also be &amp;lsquo;verified&amp;rsquo; by all
the authorized ALARMers in the VO, not only the submitter. This status indicates that a
user is happy with the provided solution. &amp;ldquo;Verified&amp;rdquo; tickets cannot be further updated,
nor re-opened.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>closed: Solved or unsolved tickets not verified by the submitter are set to “closed”
automatically after 10 working days.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="fields-to-fill-in">Fields to fill in&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Single steps of the solution process can be documented in field “Public Diary”.
Information and comments which should not be visible to the user can be put into the
“Internal diary”. When a solution is found, the modifier types the solution into the
solution field and changes status to &amp;ldquo;solved&amp;rdquo;. The “Solution” field provides 4000
characters. If 4000 characters are not sufficient, please add an attachment. After
changing status to “solved” and saving all changes, the solution is sent to the submitter
via mail automatically. Tasks for solving a ticket:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>change status to “in progress” while working on it,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fill in the solution fields and the internal diary if necessary,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>change the status to “solved” and you are done.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="reminder-emails">Reminder emails&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Reminder mails are based on the priority colours. The algorithm of setting priority
colours is described in the following chapters.
Reminder mails are sent with the reply-to address ignored - atnospam - ggus.org. All mails
sent to this mail box are deleted regularly without reading them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-are-the-priority-colours">What are the priority colours?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Priority colours are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Green: default for all new tickets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Yellow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Amber&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Red&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Light blue: for all tickets in status unsolved&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Blue: for all solved and verified tickets&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Priority colours depend on the expected response time and the expected solution time of
a ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="expected-response-time">Expected response time&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The expected response times for support units that did not agree on a dedicated quality
of service (&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-QoS-Levels">https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-QoS-Levels&lt;/a>) are listed in the relevant FAQ.
This means, the status of a ticket should be
set to another value than “assigned” for indicating that the support unit has
acknowledged the ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="expected-solution-time">Expected solution time&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The expected solution times are driven by the priority values of the tickets. All values
are working days. The higher the priority the shorter is the duration within which the
ticket is expected to be solved.
For further details please see the priority colours FAQ
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Priority-Colour">https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Priority-Colour&lt;/a> .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ticket follow-up
Ticket follow-up is done by a team at KIT (Germany) for all tickets besides operations tickets. More information on the ticket follow-up processes are available at EGI_DMSU_Ticket_Followup &lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/EGI_DMSU_Ticket_Followup">https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/EGI_DMSU_Ticket_Followup&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/GGUS:Ticket_monitoring">https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/GGUS:Ticket_monitoring&lt;/a> .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Internal: GGUS user guide</title><link>/internal/helpdesk/ggus-user-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/internal/helpdesk/ggus-user-guide/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To be removed: Moving the content of
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-User_Guide">Wiki: FAQ_GGUS-User_Guide&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>GGUS is the Helpdesk service of the EGI Infrastructure. Incident and Service
request tickets can be recorded, and their progress is tracked until the
solution. The users of the service should not need to know any of the details of
what happens to the ticket in order to get it from creation to solution.
However, an understanding of the operation of the system may be helpful to
explaining what happens when you request help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tickets can be created through the GGUS &lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/">web interface&lt;/a>, which
is described in section &amp;ldquo;Accessing the web interface to GGUS&amp;rdquo; of this note.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the ticket has entered GGUS, it is processed by assigning it to the
appropriate group to deal with the issue. The groups are generally addressed via
mailing lists, and so GGUS assigns the ticket to a group, and an email message
is sent to people on the appropriate list. Sometimes, a ticket is simple and it
is assigned to the correct group immediately and dealt with immediately.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="submitting-a-ticket-using-the-web-interface">Submitting a ticket using the web interface&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before using this route, it is essential to have either a digital certificate
installed in the appropriate manner in the web browser or an EGI Check-in
account.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="accessing-the-web-interface-to-ggus">Accessing the web interface to GGUS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If the user carries out all of the steps above, but is not registered to use
GGUS, then the home page is like the one shown in the following figure:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="UG_Unregistered_User.png" alt="GGUS home page for unregistered users">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the user faces problems with their certificate, they may get help at
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/USG_Getting_Certificate">wiki.egi.eu: Getting certificate&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For accessing GGUS users have to register first. Registration process is
described in chapter Registering at GGUS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="registering-at-ggus">Registering at GGUS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For getting supporter privileges users need to be registered. For registering at
GGUS the user should go to &lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/index.php?mode=index">GGUS home&lt;/a> and
click the &lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/index.php?mode=register_info">registration link&lt;/a>.
This link opens the registration form that the user has to fill in. In addition,
there are some links where the user can find information about X09 personal
certificates. Users who do not have a valid digital certificate can access GGUS
via EGI SSO. After filling in the registration form, the user receives an e-mail
from the GGUS team with his access data to GGUS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="accessing-ggus-with-certificate">Accessing GGUS with certificate&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The primary address of the GGUS portal is: &lt;a href="https://ggus.eu">https://ggus.eu&lt;/a>. If
the user enters this in the browser, a warning will be displayed by the browser
prompting the user to specify which certificate to use (if the user has not
selected to automatically select the certificate in the browser settings). The
reason for this warning is that GGUS has to validate the user in order to allow
access. After that, the user will no longer be asked to identify himself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The user identifies themselves with their digital certificate. At this point in
time, GGUS has identified the user and displays the start page as shown in the
following figure:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Home.png" alt="GGUS home page for recognized users">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that in this case, the user&amp;rsquo;s identity is displayed on the page and GGUS
has recognized that this user is registered to submit tickets. If authentication
by certificate fails, you will be taken to the login page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="accessing-ggus-via-egi-check-in">Accessing GGUS via EGI Check-in&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When choosing &amp;ldquo;Login via EGI AAI CheckIn&amp;rdquo; on the login page the user is guided
to the EGI Check-in page were the users Identity Provider can be selected. After
authenticating there, the user will be redirected to GGUS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-ticket-submit-form-on-web-interface">The ticket submit form on web interface&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The tickets submit form offers a set of fields which should help the user to
describe his issue as detailed as possible. Most of the fields on the submit
form are optional. Only field “Subject” is required. The submit form consists of
three main sections: the &lt;strong>user information&lt;/strong>, the &lt;strong>issue information&lt;/strong> and the
&lt;strong>routing information&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Ticket_Submit_Form.png" alt="Ticket submit form on web interface">&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>User information&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Most fields in the user information section are pre-filled by GGUS system.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>“Name/Login” is taken from the GGUS user database.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“E-Mail” is also taken from the GGUS user database.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Notification mode” defaults to “on solution”. The “Notification mode” manages
the update notifications the user receives. “On solution” means that the user
only gets notified when the ticket status is set to “solved” or a comment is
added to the public diary. Additional information is available by clicking on
the question mark on the right hand side of the field label.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“CC to” could be filled with any mail address of people who should be informed
about this ticket. Notifications are sent on every ticket update. The field
content could only be changed by people who have support access. Additional
information is available by clicking on the question mark.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Issue information&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Although only one field is mandatory in this section, as much fields as possible
should be filled with information.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>“Date/Time of issue” defaults to the submitting time. This field should be set
if the ticket is submitted much later than the issue occurred.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Subject” is a mandatory field. It should give a short description of the
issue. This field is limited to 250 characters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Describe your issue…” is limited to 4000 characters. It should be used for a
detailed description of the issue. If the user does not know which information
to add here he could click on the question mark for getting additional
information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Concerned VO” provides a drop-down list of all VOs supported by GGUS.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“VO specific” is a flag indicating whether an issue is VO specific or not. It
defaults to “no”. This flag could only be set to “yes” in combination with a
VO selected in field “Concerned VO”.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Affected Site” The site impacted by the issue. A drop-down list with all EGI
sites registered in GOC DB and OSG sites registered in OIM DB is available.
This is no routing information!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Affected ROC/NGI” The NGI/ROC impacted by the issue. A drop-down list of all
NGIs/ROCs integrated in GGUS is provided.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Ticket category” provides a drop-down list with possible values. This field
is for categorizing the issue. It defaults to “Incident”.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Type of issue” provides a drop-down list with possible values. This field is
for categorizing the issue. It defaults to “Other”.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Priority” provides a drop-down list with possible priority values. They are
“less urgent” which is the default, “urgent”, “very urgent” and “top
priority”.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Attach file(s)” offers the possibility to upload 4 attachments (e.g. log
files etc.) at a time. Attachments are limited to 2 MB. Please avoid uploading
file formats “.exe”, “.php”, “.htm(l)”.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Routing Information&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>“Notify SITE” provides a drop-down list with all EGI sites registered in GOC
DB and OSG sites registered in OIM DB. If selecting a site from the list this
site will be notified about this ticket by mail. Additionally the ticket is
assigned to the appropriate NGI/ROC directly, bypassing the TPM (Some words
about TPM). If setting a site value the appropriate NGI/ROC is set
automatically. Choosing an NGI/ROC simultaneously is not possible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Assign to ROC/NGI” provides a drop-down list of all NGIs/ROCs integrated in
GGUS. Choosing a value in this field assigns the ticket to the appropriate ROC
directly, bypassing the TPM. If assigning a ticket to an NGI/ROC choosing a
site value simultaneously is not possible.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After clicking the “Submit” button the user gets a confirmation page showing the
information submitted and the ticket ID.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Confirm_Submit.png" alt="Confirmation after ticket submit">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bypassing-the-tpm">Bypassing the TPM&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The TPM (Ticket Processing Manager) is the 1st Line Support in GGUS. Users can
bypass the TPM if they have good knowledge about where the problem is. For this
purpose at the bottom of ticket submit form there is a section &amp;ldquo;Routing
information&amp;rdquo;. Selecting either a site from the
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Notify-Sites">&amp;ldquo;Notify SITE&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> drop-down menu
or a support unit from the &amp;ldquo;Assign to support unit&amp;rdquo; drop-down menu routes the
ticket directly to the selected support unit. If selecting a site name the
NGI/ROC the site belongs to is set automatically. Hence the ticket is assigned
to the relevant NGI/ROC. Additionally the site will receive a notification about
the ticket. Selecting both, the &amp;ldquo;Notify SITE&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Assign to support unit&amp;rdquo;
is not possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tickets of type &lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Team-Tickets">TEAM&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Alarm-Tickets">ALARM&lt;/a> are always routed to
the relevant NGI/ROC by default.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="browsing-your-own-tickets">Browsing your own tickets&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After authenticating themselves the user has access to the GGUS homepage. On
this page they see a list of their own open tickets and a list of the latest
open tickets of all users (Figure 2). Below the list of the user’s own open
tickets there are two links for further browsing possibilities of the user’s own
tickets:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Show my complete ticket list,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>My Team Tickets.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The system only shows the user tickets which have been created with the same
authentication information the user is currently logged in. This means if a user
submits tickets with different certificates he does not see all of their
tickets. The reason for this is that the DN string of the certificate is stored
in each ticket. Showing all tickets of a user can be done by using the GGUS
search engine. In the GGUS search engine users can search by username amongst
others. This search will show all tickets of a user independent from the
authentication information.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="show-my-complete-ticket-list">Show my complete ticket list&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This link opens a new window showing tables of all open and closed tickets of
the user and all tickets of other users the user has subscribed to. Information
on how to subscribe to a ticket is available in section &amp;ldquo;Subscribing to a ticket
of another user.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Complete_Ticket_List.png" alt="Complete ticket list on GGUS home">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="modifying-tickets">Modifying tickets&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="modifying-your-tickets-using-the-web">Modifying your tickets using the web&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For modifying a ticket the user can just click on the ticket ID. He is guided to
another page. On this page are three main sections:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the ticket information,&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Ticket_Information.png" alt="Ticket information section">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the ticket history,&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Ticket_History.png" alt="Ticket history">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the modify section.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Modifysection_User.png" alt="Ticket modify section">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ticket information gives an overview of the personal data the user provided,
the issue description and the ticket status. The ticket history shows all
actions that have been taken to solve the ticket, the date and time these
actions have been taken and the name of the supporter who did them. In the
modify section the user can add some additional information or comment on a
question of a supporter to them. The user can add attachments, change the email
notification behavior of the system and change some other attributes of his
ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="escalating-a-ticket">Escalating a ticket&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Between the information section and the ticket history there is a button which
allows the user to escalate a ticket (Figure 9).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Escal_Button.png" alt="Escalation button">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Three escalation levels are available in GGUS:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Escalating ticket to the support unit it is assigned to.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Escalating the ticket to the support unit and the TPM on shift.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Escalating the ticket to the support unit, the TPM and the GGUS ticket
monitoring.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The escalation levels are reached one by one. It is not possible to choose one
of them. Additional information is available by clicking on the little question
mark on the left hand side of the button.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="reopen-a-solved-ticket">Reopen a solved ticket&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If a ticket is already closed it could be reopened by adding a comment and
changing the status to “reopened” in the “Modify section” (Figure 8). In this
case the support unit which solved the ticket and the TPM receive an email about
the ticket reopening.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="verifying-the-solution">Verifying the solution&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>When a ticket is solved, the user could confirm that the solution has solved
their issue by verifying it. A solution could be verified by either:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Clicking the “Verify” button in the web portal or&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Replying to the solution mail without changing anything.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Verifying a solution can help to increase the quality of solutions in GGUS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Verify_Button.png" alt="Verify button">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="modify-your-tickets-using-email">Modify your tickets using email&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Updating a ticket using email is also possible if one fundamental requirement is
achieved. The mail subject must contain the typical GGUS string “GGUS-Ticket-ID:
#Ticket-ID” where &amp;ldquo;Ticket-ID&amp;rdquo; is the ID of the ticket which should be updated.
The easiest way to do this is to reply to an update notification received from
GGUS. When updating a ticket using email the whole mail body will be added to
the ticket. Changing any other field (e.g. status, priority,…) is impossible&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ticket-participation">Ticket Participation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>GGUS system offers various possibilities for participating in tickets. They are&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the CC field,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the Involve others field and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the Subscribe field.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>An overview on these fields is given in the table below. Ticket participation
can be done by adding a valid mail address to one of these fields. Please avoid
adding closed mailing lists as such produce a lot of mail errors! Several mail
addresses have to be separated by semicolon.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>User submit&lt;/th>
&lt;th>User modify&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Supporter modify&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>CC&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yes&lt;/td>
&lt;td>No&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yes&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Involve others&lt;/td>
&lt;td>No&lt;/td>
&lt;td>No&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yes&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Subscribe&lt;/td>
&lt;td>No&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yes&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yes&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h3 id="the-cc-field">The “CC” field&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The CC field can be set by the user in the ticket submit form. Updates are only
possible for supporters for correcting or removing invalid mail addresses. Every
ticket update triggers a notification email to the mail address specified in the
“CC” field.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-involve-others-field">The “Involve others” field&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The “Involve others” field is only for supporters use. Every ticket update
triggers a notification email to the mail address specified in the “Involve
others” field.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="subscribing-to-a-ticket-of-another-user">Subscribing to a ticket of another user&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Figure 11: Ticket subscribe Every user could subscribe to tickets of other users
if he is interested in the solution of any. For subscribing a valid email
address has to be provided. The user gets a notification once the ticket is
solved. After subscribing to a ticket the user could change the notification
mode or unsubscribe if he wants to (Figure 11). Accessing the system with the
same credentials as used for subscription is necessary for this. Additional
information on subscribing to tickets is available by clicking on the question
mark at the right hand side of the label “Subscribe to this ticket”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_Subscribe.png" alt="Ticket subscribe">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="who-gets-what-email-notification-from-ggus">Who gets what email notification from GGUS?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The ticket &amp;ldquo;submitter&amp;rdquo; gets emails according to the &amp;ldquo;Notification mode&amp;rdquo; value
(s)he selected when submitting the ticket. If the selected &amp;ldquo;Notification mode&amp;rdquo;
value is &amp;ldquo;on every change&amp;rdquo; then all updates are sent to the &amp;ldquo;submitter&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;Public
Diary&amp;rdquo; entries are sent to the submitter regardless the value of the
&amp;ldquo;Notification mode&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;Internal Diary&amp;rdquo; entries never go to the &amp;ldquo;submitter&amp;rdquo;. They
are reserved for exchanges amongst supporters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The email addresses in the &amp;ldquo;Cc:&amp;rdquo; field can be entered by the &amp;ldquo;submitter&amp;rdquo; and
receive the same notifications as the submitter. &amp;ldquo;Public Diary&amp;rdquo; entries are sent
to the addresses in the &amp;ldquo;Cc:&amp;rdquo; field. &amp;ldquo;Internal Diary&amp;rdquo; entries never go to the
people in the &amp;ldquo;Cc:&amp;rdquo; field. They are reserved for exchanges amongst supporters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The email addresses in the &amp;ldquo;Involve others:&amp;rdquo; field can be entered by supporters
only and receive the same notifications as the Support Unit (SU) to which the
ticket is assigned. &amp;ldquo;Internal Diary&amp;rdquo; entries are sent to the relevant SU members
AND the people in the &amp;ldquo;Involve others:&amp;rdquo; field, as they are supposed to be
experts and contribute to the ticket solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The email address in the &amp;ldquo;Assign to one person:&amp;rdquo; field can be entered by
supporters only and receive the same notifications as the Support Unit (SU) to
which the ticket is assigned. &amp;ldquo;Internal Diary&amp;rdquo; entries are sent to the relevant
SU members AND the people in the &amp;ldquo;Involve others:&amp;rdquo; field AND the email address
in the &amp;ldquo;Assign to one person:&amp;rdquo; field as they are, all, supposed to be experts
and contribute to the ticket solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every ticket update triggers an email to the addresses in the &amp;ldquo;Cc:&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Involve
others:&amp;rdquo; and to ticket subscribers, i.e. GGUS users, unrelated to the specific
ticket, who entered their own email in the &amp;ldquo;Subscribe to this ticket&amp;rdquo; field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>GGUS email notifications highlight the fields changed with the specific update.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please avoid including closed mailing lists, e-groups in these fields as mail
delivery will fail.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="browsing-all-tickets">Browsing all tickets&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the bottom of the home page there are additional links for browsing:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Search ticket database,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show all open tickets,&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="ggus-search-engine">GGUS search engine&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For browsing all tickets the GGUS search engine is a useful tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="GGUS_User_Search.png" alt="GGUS search engine">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The GGUS search engine can be entered by clicking on link “Search ticket
database”. When accessing the search engine a default search is performed like
shown in Figure 12: GGUS search engine. Searching via Ticket ID is the easiest
and fastest way to look at a ticket. When searching via Ticket ID all other
search parameters were ignored. Besides searching for all open tickets this is
the recommended kind of search, because it avoids needless workload on the
system. When searching via ticket ID the ticket details are shown in the same
window. For getting back to the main page use the &amp;ldquo;Back&amp;rdquo; button of your browser.
The various search parameters can be combined in any way wanted except
“Untouched since”. Description fields “Keyword”, “Involved supporter” and
“Assigned to person” trigger a LIKE search to the database. Concatenating
keywords with “AND” or “OR” is currently not possible. The search can either be
started by clicking on &amp;ldquo;go&amp;rdquo; or just hitting the return key. The result of a
search by parameters is shown in the result list. For viewing ticket details
just click on the ID. A new window opens showing ticket details. For getting
back to the search result just close the window with the ticket details.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="showing-all-open-tickets">Showing all open tickets&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Clicking on this link shows all open tickets that are currently in the system.
Unlike “Showing all open tickets” the default search in GGUS search engine uses
a timeframe of one week for showing open tickets.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="contacting-the-ggus-team">Contacting the GGUS team&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Users can click on the “Envelope” icon in the menu bar for sending an email to
the GGUS team with any comments. Note: This must not be used for submitting
support requests as it does not create a ticket in the system!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ggus-development-plans">GGUS development plans&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On GGUS home page there are a couple of links where users can get more
information on the
&lt;a href="https://ggus.eu/index.php?mode=development">GGUS development plans&lt;/a> as well as
submit own feature requests. Feature requests are collected in the GGUS shopping
lists in JIRA (only for users having a CERN account) and EGI RT.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="operation-of-ggus">Operation of GGUS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The GGUS system is running on servers located at Karlsruhe Institute of
Technology (KIT), Germany. Besides the GGUS production system a backup system is
in place. Switching from production system to backup system currently needs
manual interaction. An automatic switch in case of fail-over will be
implemented. GGUS staffs at Karlsruhe are not providing support apart from
requests concerning GGUS system itself. They can be contacted by email to
support &amp;ldquo;at&amp;rdquo; ggus.org. Usual office hours for GGUS staffs are from 07:00 to
15:00 o’clock (UTC).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tpm">TPM&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>TPM (Ticket Processing Manager) is the most important part of the support system
for the grid. The purpose of TPM is:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>closing simple trouble tickets,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ensuring that other tickets are sent to the correct place for processing,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>reacting to alarms that tickets have not been processed,&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The TPM teams consist of people with a broad knowledge of the Grid.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ticket-monitoring">Ticket Monitoring&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Besides developing and maintaining GGUS system the GGUS team is also doing the
ticket monitoring. The ticket monitoring team is responsible for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Waiting-For-Submitter-Process">reminding users&lt;/a>
in case their input is required for further ticket processing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/FAQ_GGUS-Waiting-For-PT-Process">reminding supporters&lt;/a>
in case tickets are not processed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>assisting in any problem during ticket processing&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>